NETFLIX 原创喜剧特辑
["Douglas Douglass" by Pearl and the Beard plays]
♪ Douglas Douglass, apple tree ♪
♪ Have a wife, now let her be ♪
♪ Give me, give me what you got ♪
♪ I'm gonna make you what you're not ♪
♪ Douglas Douglass, prickly pear ♪
♪ Have a wife, but I don't care ♪
♪ Give me, give me all your soul... ♪
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎非常感谢
Thank you so much.
‎哈啰
Hello.
‎瞧瞧这个
Look at this!
Look at this.
‎那是…
That...
‎这是完全用蜡笔做的狗
That is a dog made entirely out of crayons.
‎我不需要
I don't need that.
‎连我现在都是问题
I'm part of the problem now.
‎这是我的黄金马桶
That's my gold toilet.
‎我根本不打算到美国
I had no plans to make it in America.
‎这不在我的计划之内
This was not on my agenda.
‎然后是因为我写了‎一出节目《娜娜》
And then what happened though is I wrote a show called Nanette,
是吧…
right, that...
‎然后…
Well, then...
‎这很明显 是吧
That's clear, isn't it?
‎所以你们才都来此
That's why you're here.
‎你们来这里 ‎不是因为我先前的旧作 对吧
You're not here because of my back catalog of prior, are you?
‎而这也正是要问的问题 ‎如果你是因为《娜娜》来此
Which does beg the question, if you're here because of Nanette...
‎为什么
why?
我 ???
I ???
‎别误会我的意思 ‎那是个很棒的节目 很有实力
Like, don't get me wrong, it was a good show. Solid bit of work.
‎我也非常喜欢
I'm quite fond.
‎但这是个口味特定的特别节目
But it was a particular show of a very particular flavor.
‎如果是这原因让你来… ‎你究竟还想看什么
And if that is what has brought... What the fuck are you expecting from this show?
‎很抱歉 如果是要看更多创伤 ‎我已经都讲完了
Because I'm sorry, if it's more trauma, I... I am fresh out.
‎要是我早知道创伤是非常受欢迎的喜剧内容
Had I known just how wildly popular trauma was going to be in the context of comedy,
‎我该好好规划一下我的创伤
I might have budgeted my shit a bit better.
‎真的啦 ‎我可以靠创伤创业
Honestly. I could have built quite the career out of it.
At least a trilogy.
‎至少分三部曲
‎但我像个白痴 把我的创伤蛋全都放在同一个篮子里
But I went and put all my trauma eggs into one basket like a fucking idiot,
‎结果我傻呼呼地在这
and now here we are.
‎你们还想听
You want more?
‎就这阵掌声 我好奇问一下
Just out of curiosity, by round of applause,
‎谁没看过《娜娜》
who has not seen Nanette?
‎那我就更搞不清楚 ‎你为何会在这里了
Even less of an idea why the fuck you're here.
‎当然 欢迎
I mean, welcome.
‎你很不错 愿意试一下
Good on you, taking a punt.
‎别担心 没关系
And-- And don't worry, it's fine.
‎这节目不是看你 ‎有没有看过《娜娜》
This show does not depend on you having seen Nanette.
‎我没那么有自信 但是…
I'm not that kind of confident, but...
‎就边走边瞧了
We'll see what happens.
‎但除了创伤
But other than trauma,
‎我根本不知道大家 ‎对这节目期待什么
you know, I have no way of telling what people are expecting from this show.
‎但我所决定的倒是非常可能
Right? But what I've decided is possible
‎就是让我直接告诉你
is for me to just tell you.
‎接下来就是如此
And that's what's gonna happen.
‎这就是我满足你期待的方法
That's how I'm going to meet your expectations.
‎为了你们 现在做调整
-By adjusting them for you now. -
‎所以他们绝对是你想看到的
So they are exactly what you're gonna get.
‎然后我满足你 你会说“她好厉害” ‎是 我的确是
Then I'll meet them and you'll go, "She's very good." And, yes, I am,
但我作弊
but I cheat.
So that's what's gonna happen before the show even begins, right?
‎所以甚至节目还没开始 ‎就会发生这样的事 对吗
‎我将向你们巨细靡遗的描述
I'm going to give you a very detailed, blow-by-blow description
‎这节目将要展开的内容
of exactly how the show is going to unfold.
‎的确有这样的期待存在
Now this setting of expectations does go on a bit.
‎让我得要删掉实际的节目才能符合 但是…
I've had to cut the actual show in order to fit it in, but...
‎我相信很值得
I believe it's worth it, you know?
‎满足你的期待 就是我的职责
Like, to be able to meet your expectations, it's my job.
‎我们就面对现实吧 ‎这是我的第二张期待的畅销
And let's face it, this is my difficult second album,
‎这也是我第十‎以及有些人的第一次
that is also my tenth and some people's first.
‎其实压力超大
You know, it's a lot of pressure.
‎来看看你的期待吧
So let's set your expectations.
‎节目开始时… ‎
When the show begins...
节目真正开始时…
When the show actually begins...
‎这还不是 别紧张
This is not it. Don't panic.
‎开始的时候 我会用‎生活观察的笑料作为开始
When it begins, I'm gonna kick things off with a bit of observational comedy.
‎是吧 就象是“你们有没有注意过… ‎那怎么了 ”
Right? A bit of, you know, "Have you ever noticed... What's up with that?"
‎我就会开始说这鬼话 ‎
That shit. That's what I'm starting with.
‎这其实不是很好 我也完全对你们老实说
And look, it's not very good, I'm gonna be perfectly honest with you,
因为我其实观察力很差
because I'm not very observant.
‎基本上呢
-Typically speaking... -
就是过目即忘
vague as fuck, right?
‎这么说吧 我的观察就是美国人
Now, fair warning, my observations will be about Americans,
‎普遍说来 就是你们大家
which is, broadly speaking, you lot.
Right? So...
‎对吧 所以…
‎抱歉 取笑美国人
And-- And, sorry, but making fun of Americans
仍旧技术上来说很有梗
is still technically punching up,
‎虽然就快没机会了
although that window is closing.
‎的确
It is.
‎所以…
And so...
‎我只是顺手之便
I'm just making hay, you know.
‎因为我不会说俄文 ‎所以我真的得…
'Cause I can't speak Russian, so I've really gotta...
‎抓住机会
get it in while I can. I don't know.
‎我也该警告你
I should just also warn you,
‎在我嘲笑美国人期间
during the bit where I make fun of Americans...
‎你可能会感觉受伤
your feelings will smart,
‎因为我就是会直接取笑
because I will be making fun of you there.
‎我希望你们先有心理准备 好吗
I just need you to expect that, right?
‎我绝对会耻笑 这是我老家的说法 ‎你也不会在乎
I will be taking the absolute piss, as we say back home, not that you care.
‎然后你坐在那里 ‎可能反应像这样…
And so you'll be sitting there, just going, "Oh."
‎公平说来 ‎我不想否定你的感觉
And fair enough. I don't want to deny your feelings.
‎拜托 拥抱你的感受 ‎彻底感受一下
Have them, please. Let them run through you, definitely.
‎但我强烈建议
But what I would suggest, strongly,
别钻进牛角尖里
is that you do not invest in those feelings.
‎别让情绪冲昏你的头 ‎因为这个节目
Don't let them get a grip on you, because what this show is,
‎应该是个浪漫喜剧
if anything, is a romantic comedy.
‎为了节目最后 ‎不好的开始就至关重要了
So it's just, to that end, important that we get off to a shaky start.
‎就这样…别钻牛角尖
So that's all... Just don't invest.
‎感受 但别钻牛角尖
Feel, but don't invest.
‎跟着我 相信我
Just go with me. Trust me.
‎不要相信我
Don't trust me.
‎不要相信那个人
Don't trust that person.
‎总之…
Anyway...
‎就这样 对吧 ‎就这样开始
That bit, right? So that's how it's gonna start.
‎观察日常的喜剧
Bit of observational comedy.
‎接下来我呢 ‎就要告诉你一个故事
Then what I'm going to do is I am going to tell you a story
‎关于白天发生在‎狗公园的神秘习题
about a curious incident that took place in the dog park in the daytime.
‎这故事很有趣
Now, it's a fun story. It's a fun story.
‎透过这整个故事 ‎在同意下 我将会接触到
And throughout that story, I will touch on, with consent,
‎这节目最主要的主题 ‎所以你们要特别留意
most of the major themes of the show, so watch out for those.
‎同时也包含不少
And it will also include a fair dose
‎我所谓的温和和蔼的父权芒刺
of what I call a gentle and very good-natured needling of the patriarchy.
‎节目也包含这元素
-So that is in there. -
‎所以非常重要…
So it's very important...
‎要有心理准备很重要 ‎因为节目里绝对有
It's very important that you expect that, because it is there,
‎如果你不喜欢
and if that's not your thing...
‎离开
leave.
‎我已经不断地警告你了 ‎就走吧
I've given you plenty of warning. Just go.
‎走吧 玻璃心 ‎头也不要回地离去
Off you pop, man-flakes. Out you go. Go on with you.
‎在那个故事后 ‎我会再说一则故事
Now, after that story, I'm gonna tell another story.
‎什么 瞧我说的 ‎我知道 经典
What? Look at me go. I know. Classic.
‎第二则故事 ‎是我收到的误诊
The second story is about a misdiagnosis I received,
‎我会把误诊归咎于厌女症
and I'm gonna blame that misdiagnosis squarely on misogyny,
‎因为这是真的
because it's true.
‎现在 再之后…
Now, after...
‎再之后…那只是芒刺
After that... That's just the needle.
‎如果感觉痛的话 ‎趁还能走路 就先离开
If that hurts, get out while you can still walk. Now...
‎故事的最后 我会进行我所谓的“套恶”
at the end of that story, I'm going to do a bit of what I call "hate baiting."
‎我对痛恶我的人设套 ‎这是个非常复杂的概念
It's where I bait my haters. It's a very complex idea.
‎我采取的方式是 ‎我只会说一件事
Now the way that I'll do that is I will just say a thing.
‎我绝对不会搞笑
And I will make no fucking effort to make it funny.
‎我就大辣辣地说出 ‎然后就搁在那儿
I'll just say it and leave it there.
‎我不在乎
I don't care.
‎我强烈建议你不要…
Now, I would strongly recommend that you do not...
‎你不要入套
You do not take the bait.
‎不要对号入座 不是说你
Do not take the bait. It's not for you.
‎对你不好 你会口吐白沫
It's bad for you. You'll be all Frothy McFroth Face.
‎就搁在那边就好
Like, just leave it there.
‎然后呢 我就进入笑话桥段
Then what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna move into the joke section,
‎也就是说笑话 对吧
which is jokes, right?
‎所以我才说是笑话桥段 ‎笑话一个接一个
That's why I call it the joke section. It's just joke after joke.
‎真的…很经典
It's really... It's classic.
‎如果在那期间
Now, if in that bit,
‎若你觉得被我所说的冒犯
you find yourself offended by anything I say in the joke section,
请记住都只是笑话
please just remember they are just jokes.
‎就算你发现自己 ‎周遭的人都在哈哈大笑
Even if you find yourself surrounded by people who are laughing
‎那些让你“不苏湖”的话题
at something you find objectionable...
‎只要记住喜剧的黄金准则
just remember the golden rule of comedy, which is,
if you're in a minority, you do not matter.
‎也就是只要你是少数族群 ‎你便举无轻重
‎的确是 别怪我 ‎这准则不是我写的
You don't. Don't blame me. I didn't write the rules of comedy.
‎男人写的 怪他们 ‎我会 挺净化人心的
Men did. Blame them. I do. It's cathartic.
‎现在…
Now...
‎来了 ‎笑话桥段的功用 ‎就是让节目渐入高潮
There we are. The joke section works to really ramp the show up,
‎语调、节奏 ‎加上我对父权的讽刺
in tone, in pace, and also in my needling of the patriarchy.
‎届时 小小的刺激就变成了尖锐的长枪
By that stage, the needle will have become a jousting stick.
‎是的 说是尖锐的长枪
Yep. And then, with said jousting stick,
‎意思就是准备对痛恶我的人‎再开一个屁眼
I'm going to set about tearing my haters a new asshole.
‎是的 又快又准
Yep. Quick as you like.
‎超新的洞
Brand-spanking new.
‎我所用的方式 正是痛恶我的人指控我所用的方式
And the way that I'll do that is by doing exactly what my haters accuse me of doing,
‎也就是教训你
which is lecturing you.
‎在节目当中 我将会说教
So in the middle of the show, I'm giving a big, old lecture.
‎曲折 那就好笑了
- -The twist? It's funny.
‎超好笑 对吧
It's fucking funny. Right?
‎也正是痛恶我的人 ‎指控我别当的
Which is exactly what my haters accuse me of not being.
‎让他们不断反覆循环 ‎他们可能会死 愿上帝保佑了
So that's gonna send them on a bit of a loop. May kill them. Fingers crossed.
‎在这个阶段 ‎你也许当下会很纳闷
Now, at this stage, you're probably wondering, and rightly so,
‎我为何要针对痛恶我的人
why would I focus on my haters?
‎我为何要这么做 ‎感觉很纵容自己 是的
Why would I do that? That is self-indulgent. Yes.
‎是的 我拜读过‎泰勒·斯威夫特所有作品
And, yes, I have read all of Taylor Swift's work.
‎我知道我们这年代的圣贤
I am aware of the great sage of our age.
‎我的确明白痛恶我的人 ‎将会不断怀恨下去
I do understand that haters are just gonna hate, hate, hate, hate.
‎痛恶
Hate.
‎不断痛恶
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate, hate.
‎她说得没错 ‎他们会不断重复
And she's not wrong. They are repetitive.
-So why wouldn't I... -
‎所以我为何不…
‎我为何不追随她 然后摆脱掉
Why wouldn't I follow her lead and just shake it off?
‎我为何不这么做
Why wouldn't I do that?
‎就抖掉…
Just shake, shake, shake...
‎这是原因之一
It's one reason. That is one reason.
‎另一个原因是我不相信 ‎我们的朋友小泰泰
The other reason is because I'm not convinced our friend Tay Tay...
‎真的是仇恨犯罪下的受害者
has been a victim of an actual hate crime.
‎而我曾遭遇过
And I have.
‎所以自然我们对于网络仇恨处理方式不同
So, naturally, the way that we deal with online hate is going to differ.
‎就我个人 我喜欢当点心吃
Personally, I like to snack on it.
‎是的 吃吃吃 ‎这身材不是凭空而来的
Yep. Nom, nom, nom. This body doesn't just happen.
‎我是大啖仇恨的美女
I am a real hate patootie.
‎在我处理完痛恶我的人后
Now, after I've dealt with my haters there,
‎我会替他们奏管风琴赋格曲
sent them on their little fugue spiral,
‎然后在节目中 ‎我会做个巨大改变
what I'll do then is change gears dramatically in the show,
‎是藉由告诉你们 ‎我患有自闭症的方式
and I will do that by telling you that I have autism.
‎我说出口的方式 ‎就像是揭开一个大秘密
And I'm going to tell you in such a way that it's gonna sound like a big reveal.
‎但其实应该也不惊讶
But it just... it really shouldn't come as a surprise.
‎我刚不就说了 而且…
I've just told you. And...
‎节目到了那个点
And also because everything in the show up until that point
‎其实已经数度警告 ‎我有自闭症了
works as a big sequence of red flags that I have autism.
‎老实说 这沿路上都是 ‎我留下的面包屑
Honestly, I have Hansel and Greteled the fuck out of it.
‎都在那里
It is all there.
‎但因为我破坏了我的惊喜
But because I've spoiled my own surprise there,
‎为了再度揭开
in order to make it a big reveal again,
‎我得靠舞台与灯光的效果
I have to rely on staging and lighting tricks
‎让你们觉得 ‎“哇 这是个大秘密”
to bring it in so you go, "Oh, it's a big reveal."
‎所以灯光会照过来 ‎我会站在脚凳上
So the lights are gonna come in, I'm gonna sit on this stool here,
‎然后就象是“现在 当下…”
and it's gonna be, "Right, now..."
‎但没效 因为你们不是笨蛋
And-- And it's not going to work, because you're not fucking idiots.
‎然后再之后…
And then, after that bit,
‎我将会稍稍转到反疫苗运动
I'm gonna do a tiny bit of gear about the anti-vax movement.
‎听听你们自己
Listen to yourselves.
-Listen to yourselves. -
‎这…你并不特别
This is... You're not unusual.
‎是吧 我世界巡回这节目表演
Right, I've toured this show around the world
‎我可以说没有任何地方的‎任何观众
and I can report that no audience anywhere
‎知道在一提到反疫苗运动时
has known how to collectively respond to just the mention...
‎该如何做出集体反应
- -of the anti-vax movement.
‎大概只要说“反疫苗” ‎大家就会说“哈哈 不”
Pretty much, you just say "anti-vax" and people are like, "Ha, ha, no!"
‎这一定会很有趣
So that's gonna be fun.
‎我反疫苗的话题素材‎会跟节目其他的内容风格不同
Now, my anti-vax material is different in tone to the rest of the show.
‎到最后 你可能会觉得
At the end of it, you'll sit there and go, "Ooh.
‎“她真的需要一个抒发的管道”
Well, she just needed to get that off her chest."
- -And it's true, I do. And I will.
‎这是真的 我一定会的
‎但重点是 ‎我从来没碰过
But here's the thing. I've never met a joke...
‎我会想收回的笑话
that I haven't wanted to call back.
‎我从来没碰过
I've never met a joke...
‎各位好
G'day.
‎我从自嘲…
I've never meta...
‎自嘲
Meta joke.
这是双关语
That's a pun.
‎跟上 好吗
Catch up. Right?
‎这是节目充满双关语 ‎会有很多双关语
Now, this is a very pun-heavy show. You need to expect a lot of puns.
‎还会有一个路易CK式笑话
And you also need to expect one Louis C.K. joke.
‎瞧瞧这反应
Listen to that.
‎他就像是个喜剧反疫苗 ‎对吧
He is like the anti-vax of comedy, isn't he?
‎我只有一个笑话 ‎但不是刚才说的
Now, I only have one joke. That wasn't it, by the way.
‎节目还没开始 ‎现在还只是前奏
The show hasn't started. We're still in the prelude.
‎这个笑话…非常棒
The one joke... It's very good.
‎我只需要一个笑话 ‎一个好的笑话
I only need one. It's a good... It's a good joke.
‎那天我休假 不拿笔 ‎吃了饼干 把笑话写出来
It was a day off, pens down, have a biscuit, the day I wrote that joke.
‎超棒的笑话
Fucking good joke.
‎我非常确定 我的路易CK笑话 ‎会是让麦克风掉落的经典
I am so solid, my Louis C.K. joke, it's a mic drop moment.
‎我会让让麦克风掉落
And I will drop the mic.
‎不管你们的反应如何 ‎我就会直接丢…
Doesn't matter how you respond, I will drop...
- -the mic.
‎麦克风
‎但我不会真的丢
Except I won't drop the mic,
‎因为你没不知道 ‎但已经有心里准备
because you don't know this yet, but you do,
‎我有自闭症 而且我发现 ‎巨大吵杂声很舒压
I have autism and I find loud noises quite distressing.
‎所以我就会直接 ‎把这鬼东西放在这里
So what I'll do instead is I'll just place the fucker directly on the ground there.
‎就放在这里
-Just pop it down now. -
‎当然这会带走当下的戏剧效果
Now, that will take away from the theatrics of the moment,
‎但先别当个健全主义份子
absolutely, but let's not be ableist about this.
‎路易CK笑话有趣的地方在于
The interesting thing about the Louis C.K. joke
‎是节目很后面的事情
is that it happens very late in the show,
‎后面到你都忘记 ‎你会听到我讲个路易CK的笑话
so late you will have forgotten that I told you to expect a Louis C.K. joke,
‎这表示我在你的欢笑蛋糕上
which means I've just added an extra layer of mirth
‎又加了一层
to your laugh cake.
‎是的 当你在笑的时候 ‎你绝对会 真的很棒
Yep, because when you laugh at it... and you will. It's very good.
‎你在笑的时候
As you're laughing at it,
‎你就会想起我会说个‎路易CK笑话给你听
you will remember that I told you to expect a Louis C.K. joke
‎发现你根本忘记
and realize you'd forgotten.
‎所以你会这样笑
Which means you'll laugh like this. "Ha, ha-- Oh!"
‎也表示我又加了第三层
Which means I've just added a third layer.
‎因为你想起来的时候 你会说“这就是她说她会说的笑话”
Because when you realize, you'll go, "That's exactly what she said she'd do!"
‎所以你就会这样笑…“哈哈，欧，嘿”
-So you'll laugh, "Ha, ha-- Oh! Hey!" -laughter]
‎一次两次三次 女人能做到 （歌曲《 ‎一辈子身边的女人》） 是吧
It's once, twice, three times a lady can do that, you see. Hey?
‎当然在对的手里
In the right hands, of course.
‎在对的手里 其实你只需要手
In the right hands. And you only need hands.
‎谁知道 大多女人知道
Who knew? Most women.
‎现在…
Now...
‎反疫苗话题之后…
After the anti-vax material,
‎我将要试图让你进入我的自闭症
what I'm going to do is I'm going to try and let you in on my experience of autism.
‎我的方式是说个我跟可能
And I'll do that by telling a story about, uh, my relationship to a penguin
‎在或不在箱子里企鹅之间关系的故事
that may or may not be inside a box.
‎我也不能保证有没有道理
I can't promise you it'll make more sense then either.
‎然后我再说教 做节目的结尾
And then I'll finish the show out with another lecture.
‎什么 还讲道理 谁知道
What? Another lecture? Who knew?
‎我知道 你现在知道了 ‎所以才在现在说明
I did. Now you do. That is what is going on here.
‎我承认节目的最后
Now, I will admit, the-- the last part of the show there,
‎我将会比节目一开始更讨喜一些
I will be much more likable than I am in the beginning.
‎几近可爱边缘
Borderline adorable.
‎你可能在想
Now, you're probably wondering
‎我为何不全力以赴
why wouldn't I start with my best foot forward,
‎发射可爱子弹 ‎我为何不这么做
adorable guns a-blazing? Why wouldn't I do that?
‎为何一开始要让人不喜欢
Why would I start off being a bit unlikable?
‎因为这是个自闭症的节目
Because this is a show about autism.
‎自闭症的人总是 ‎让人第一印象深刻
And people with autism rarely make a good first impression.
‎大部分的人因此对我们退避三舍
And most people tend to write us off because of that.
‎这是反馈给坚持不懈之人的节目
So this is a show that rewards people who persevere.
‎那些愿意穿越柳暗而看见花明的人
Who go beyond their discomfort just to see what's on the other side of the spectrum.
‎对于那些人而言 ‎这节目绝对就是浪漫喜剧了
For those people, this show does work like a romantic comedy.
‎理论上来说是的 ‎因为理论最迷人
Theoretically, 'cause theories are sexy.
‎节目就这样
Now, that's it. That's the show.
‎这就是你所期待能看见的一切 ‎期待已经设定完毕
That's everything you can expect. Expectations have been set.
‎现在就上台一鞠躬
So the show starts now.
‎你有没有注意到过…
Have you ever noticed...
‎美国人是如何…
how Americans...
‎变得没那么笨
are not stupid?
‎这有问题吗
What's up with that?
‎你们不笨
You're not stupid.
‎我发现这点时超失望
I was so disappointed to discover that.
‎因为我被你们误导
Because I had been led to believe, by you...
‎你们蠢到爆
that you are as dumb as bricks.
‎然后见到你们大家 ‎根本不是这样
And then I meet you all, and then you're not.
‎当然还是有配额 ‎我们都有 但你们不…
I mean, you've got your quota, as have we all, but you're not...
‎你知道你们如何 ‎在人文上非常有自信
Do you know what you are? You're culturally confident.
‎你们非常不错
Good on you, I say. Good on you.
And you know who else had that skill set?
‎真的不错 你们知道 ‎谁还有这种本领
‎古罗马人
The ancient Romans.
‎他们曾经一度辉煌
And things worked out well for them... for a bit.
‎别钻牛角尖 没事的
Don't invest. It's all right.
‎撑住 没事 美国 加油
Hold true. You're all right. You're all right, America. Hang in there.
Invest a little.
‎可以钻一点点了
‎我认为是你们的自信 ‎让你们愚蠢
Now, I think it's your confidence that makes you stupid.
‎先缓缓 别钻牛角尖
Bear with me. Don't invest.
‎老实说 我真的觉得 ‎因为自信…
Honestly, I do, because confidence...
‎自信让人愚蠢 ‎这点我非常有自信
Confidence makes you stupid, and I'm very confident in that opinion.
‎因为你们对于美国这身份 ‎非常的有自信
Because you're so confident in your American-inity
‎让你自恃一切 ‎因为是美国 一定是对的 是吧
that you hang onto things just 'cause it's American and it must be right, right?
‎你的自恃就是因为是美国
You hang onto things just 'cause it's American,
‎你所自恃的证明非常愚蠢
even if the thing you cling to is proof of literal stupidity.
‎我说个例子 一个就够了
And I'll give you an example. I only need one.
‎我们加油…
Now, we fossil fuel...
‎我们在澳洲给汽车加油 ‎跟你们加的油一样 对吧
We fossil fuel our cars with the same stuff you do, in Australia, right?
‎我们用的是“石油“
We fossil fuel it with petroleum.
‎因为石油挺难念的
Now, "petroleum" is very heavy of the syllable.
‎我们没时间 超忙的 ‎没时间念这么难的字
We don't have time. We're busy people. We don't have time for syllables.
‎哈哈哈 这就是我们擅长的
"LOL." You know, this is where we're at.
‎我们很聪明地把“石油” ‎变得好念 对吧
So we've wisely shortened "petroleum" here and there, right?
‎在澳洲 我们把“石油”简称做“汽油”
In Australia, we've shortened "petroleum" to "petrol."
‎我不是在自夸 这不是… ‎我们只是不讲了
Now, I'm not bragging. That's not... Like, we've just stopped talking.
‎就这样自然演变 我们就说“汽油”
That is all that has happened there. We're just like, "Petrol."
‎你们倒是更深一步发挥想象力
You have dug a lot deeper into the hat of imagination
‎来简称“石油”
for your shortening of "petroleum,"
‎因为你们称做“瓦斯”
because you've shortened it to "gas."
‎石油有意思的是它是液体
Now, the interesting thing about petroleum is that it is a liquid.
‎而瓦斯就它天杀的定义上而言 ‎非常有意思的是…
And the interesting thing about gas, by its very fucking definition...
‎它根本不是液体
- -is that it is not a liquid!
‎但你们比较喜欢煤气化科学 ‎还是随便了
But you guys would rather gaslight science, or flood it.
‎我根本不懂你们脑袋里在想什么
I don't know how the thinking happens in your head!
But you will not change,
‎但你们不会改变
‎因为你们会说“这是对的 ‎我们想过而且我们是美国人”
'cause you're like, "It's right, 'cause we thought of it and we're Americans."
‎但这不对 超蠢
But it's not right. It is dumb in the face!
‎我开始在这里巡回时 有人‎跟我说要把词汇改得美国一点
When I first started touring here, I was told I should Americanize my language.
‎而我的回答是
To which I responded,
‎“去你的 美国化这字的结尾不是Z 混帐”
"Fuck off. Americanise is not spelled with a 'Z,' fuckers."
‎老实说 美国就象是个白异男文化
Honestly, Americans are like the straight, white man of cultures.
‎你们说“口以” ‎就只在乎这点而已
You say, "To-may-to," that's all you care about.
‎见鬼了 我才不会 ‎屈服在你们的自信下
Like, fuck off. I will not bow to your confidence.
‎我不会说“汗衫”
I will not say, "Sweater."
‎我会说“套头衫” ‎你们自己调适
I will be saying, "Jumper," and you can cope.
‎我不是说“套头衫”比较对 ‎而是“套头衫”本来就对
I'm not suggesting that "jumper" makes sense. "Jumper" makes fuck all sense.
‎但这样改听起来很好玩
But what it does do is it sounds fun.
‎“我要穿套头衫”
"I'm gonna put on a jumper."
‎“好的 祝你愉快 闪边去”
"Oh, mate, you're gonna have a good day. Off you pop."
‎但你们穿汗衫
But you guys, you put on a sweater.
‎“是的 我身上上半身的衣服 ‎是用来吸我身体的汗”
"Yeah, this is the top I wear to soak up the wet of my body. Mmm."
‎饼干
Biscuit.
‎是吧
Deal with it.
‎我节目后面叫某个人 ‎混帐饼干（短肥屌） 而我这么说…
I call someone a dick biscuit later in the show, and when I say...
‎因为我是大人了
'Cause I'm mature.
‎当…
And when...
‎我说“饼干” ‎你们所谓的“曲奇饼”
I say, "Biscuit," I mean what you call a cookie.
‎而不是你们所谓的小面包 ‎那个我叫做粗司康
And not what you call a biscuit, which is what I call a rogue scone.
-That is a scone what forgot its manners. -
‎那个是忘记规矩的司康
‎完全失控
It is out of control.
‎但我不会说“混帐曲奇饼”
But I will not say, "Dick cookie."
‎我绝对不会 ‎我拒绝 因为辞不达意
I will not. I refuse, 'cause it doesn't work.
‎当你叫混帐饼干时 ‎表示我们不喜欢他们
When you call someone a dick biscuit, it means we don't want to like them.
‎而“混帐饼干”就有这个含意
And "dick biscuit" does that.
‎听起来他们就在史莱哲林
It sounds like they're in Slytherin.
‎混帐饼干
- -Dick Biscuit.
‎混帐曲奇饼
Dick cookie? Yeah, it's all right.
‎雷文克劳
It's like Ravenclaw.
‎虽然搞不清楚他们在干嘛 ‎但他们好像还好 还可以
No one really knows what's up with them, but they seem all right. They seem fine.
‎如果我说考克毕斯卡提 ‎（义式坚果饼干）医师…
And I've decided that Dr. Cock Biscotti...
Hufflepuff.
‎赫夫帕夫
‎绝对是赫夫帕夫
That is definitely Hufflepuff.
Dr. Cock Biscotti.
‎考克毕斯卡提医师
‎我根本不考虑葛来分多 ‎去他们的
And I've put no thought into Gryffindor whatsoever, 'cause fuck 'em.
‎他们都象是霍格华兹李的白异男
They are like the straight, white man of Hogwarts.
"What about Hermione?" She's probably a terf. Fuck her.
‎“那妙丽呢 ” ‎她可能是个排跨基女 去她的
‎一记重击
Punching up.
‎我也做了些让步 ‎我不是蛮横不讲理
I mean, I have made some concessions for you. I'm not a monster.
‎我会说“沃里” ‎《沃里在哪里 》
Like, I'll say, "Waldo." Where's Waldo?
‎我其实知道他叫威利 ‎看吧 没这么难
I've always known him as Wally, but, look, it's not that hard.
‎“沃里” 就得了
"Waldo." Did it.
‎关键就在这里 找到沃里 ‎就能找到威利
So the trick is there. If you find Waldo, you've found Wally.
‎他们两个是同一人
-It's the same guy. -
‎我很乐意接受你们的赘词
And I've happily taken on a lot of your wordage.
‎你们的语言里很多 ‎美国 我喜欢
There's a lot about your language I like, America.
像是“芝麻叶”
Like "arugula."
Yes, please.
‎是的 来一份
‎我们称之为“火箭”
We call that stuff "rocket."
‎火箭滚开 我要芝麻叶 ‎听起来象是小丑车喇叭
Fuck off, rocket. I want arugula. It sounds like a clown car horn.
‎是的 麻烦 芝麻叶
Yes, please. Arugula!
‎还有铝
And aluminum. Mm-hmm. Yes.
‎是的 我们的拼法一样 ‎但念法不同
We have the same word, but we say, "Alu-min-ium."
‎可以带点情趣的语调念时 ‎为何要这么说
Why would you say, "Aluminium," when you can flirt it?
"Al-u-minum."
‎铝
‎“别闹了 美国”
"Stop it, America."
‎还有“你们大伙” 是的 拜托
And, "Y'all?" Oh, yes, please!
‎“感谢你们大伙
"Thanks all y'all for y'all.
‎我带你们大伙 我爱你们大伙”
I'm taking y'all. I love y'all."
‎因为“你们大伙”是最棒、最包含
Because "y'all" is the best, most inclusive
‎第二人称复数的英语系的字
second-person, plural pronoun in the English-speaking world.
‎感谢 南方 好盟军
Thank you, the South. What an ally.
‎对于“小妹妹”我就不确定了
I'm in two minds about "fanny."
‎单纯这个字
Just the word.
‎这里“小妹妹”指的是屁股后面、臀部、屁屁
'Cause, here, "fanny" is your butt. Your rear end, your backside, your bum.
‎在澳洲 “小妹妹”则是 ‎专门指的是女孩子那里
In Australia, "fanny" refers specifically to the lady front bum,
‎这是广义的说法
to use inclusive language. I don't know.
‎当我第一次在美国听见‎大家都有“小妹妹” 我觉得挺酷的
And when I first heard that everyone in America has a fanny, I thought, "Cool.
‎非常酷
Cool, cool, cool.
‎我象是到了勒斯博岛 ‎来去吧
I'm going to the Isle of Lesbos. Giddy up."
‎只是个玩笑 不该出现
That's just a joke. It doesn't belong there.
‎肯定是从玩笑桥段跑出来 ‎我道歉
Must have snuck out of the joke section. Apologies there.
‎不 我很久以前就知道 ‎“小妹妹”的差异性了
No, I've known about the fanny discrepancy for a very long time.
‎我从没忘记我发现
I will never forget the day
‎“小妹妹”在这里意思 ‎不同于家乡的那天
I discovered "fanny" meant a different thing here than it does back home.
‎当时我在学校 看一本书 ‎是一本没翻译的美国书
I was at school, I was reading a book. It was an American book. Untranslated.
‎我向来还蛮有语言天赋的
I've always had a bit of a gift for the languages.
‎只是一本四个小孩的探险故事
Now, it was just a random children's book about four kids on an adventure
‎而探险里…
and part of their adventure...
‎显然这四个小孩滑下山丘
Apparently these four children slid down a hill.
‎靠屁股（小妹妹）滑下去
On their fannies.
‎我一整个下午恍神
And I lost an afternoon.
‎我恍神了一个下午 ‎想把这件事搞懂
I lost an afternoon trying to make that work in my mind's eye,
‎因为滑下坡根本不是这种方法啊
because that is not how you go down a hill!
‎如果你这样滑下去 ‎绝对自愿 肯定是跌倒
If you go down a hill like that, that is not a decision. You've tripped.
‎而四个小孩同时跌倒的机率 ‎是有多高…
And what are the chances of four children synchronized-tripping...
‎而且作者还觉得稀松平常
and it not rating a mention from the narrator?
‎怎么可能
Fuck all.
‎所以为何要选择这样下去
So why would you choose to go down like that?
‎不符合空气力学
It's not aerodynamic,
‎我不在乎你怎么觉得 ‎那里可很脆弱
and I don't care how you identify, that is vulnerable.
‎你怎么开始下去 ‎是头先下去 还是脚
And which way do you go? Head first? Feet first?
‎都不符合空气力学 那膝盖勒
Well, neither are aerodynamic.
‎那膝盖勒
And what the fuck do you do with your knees?
‎我可能该告诉你 ‎“道格拉斯”是什么意思
I should probably tell you what "Douglas" means.
‎因为这里的意思 ‎跟我家乡的意思简直天壤之别
'Cause it means a very different thing here than it does back home.
‎在澳洲 道格拉斯是 ‎袋鼠子宫的俚语
In Australia, a Douglas is slang for a kangaroo's uterus.
‎才不是
It's fucking not.
‎我们为何有这种俚语
Like, why would we have slang for that?
‎搞什么飞机
For fuck's sake.
‎澳洲人根本没这么道地 拜托
Australians are not even that Australian. Come on.
‎那只是我狗的名字
It was just my dog's name.
‎我以我的狗命名这节目
I've named this show after my dog.
‎他叫道格拉斯
His name's Douglas.
‎你们鼓掌还蛮奇怪 但挺酷的
It's weird that that's the thing you clap, but cool.
‎“非常好 你替你的狗取名字 ‎再取同样的节目名称
"Well done, you named your dog and then your show after the same...
You're not so weird anymore."
‎你其实也没这么奇怪”
‎道格拉斯是我第一只狗
Douglas is my first dog. Douglas is my first dog.
‎现在长大了 在成长过程中 ‎我养过很多狗
As an adult. I had lots of dogs when I was growing up.
‎我家人也养过几只 ‎我们住在繁忙的街道上
Our family went through them a bit. We lived on a busy road.
‎好 你们了解这情况
All right. That's where you're at.
听着 只是…
-Look, it just... -
really paints a picture of a time and a place. Look... [chuckles]
‎真的具体描绘出时间地点
‎道格拉斯很好 ‎我不再住在繁忙的街道上了
Douglas is fine. I don't live on a busy road anymore.
‎我把它照顾得很好
I take good care of the boy.
‎我带它到狗公园去
I take him to the dog park.
‎固定去狗公园的人
And anyone who goes to a dog park on the regular
‎都知道其实在狗公园
knows that no good conversation is ever had...
‎并没有什么有趣话题
- -at a dog park.
‎那里只是八卦之处
They are just festivals of small talk,
‎那里不是我天生的生长地
and that is not my natural habitat.
‎你还不知道原因 ‎但会知道的
You don't know why yet, but you do.
‎现在我来说个故事
Now, I want to tell you a story
‎就说有一次我在狗公园 ‎一场相当糟糕的对话
about a terrible conversation I had at the dog park once.
‎有个家伙朝我走来
This bloke just walks up to me.
‎他带了只狗 不是什么怪咖 ‎跟地点相关的人士
I mean, he had a dog. He wasn't just being creepy. He had context.
‎我要告诉你
I want to tell you this.
‎这跟故事无关 ‎但我只是要你明白
It's not pertinent to the story, but I want you to know.
‎他的狗穿鞋
His dog had shoes on.
‎但他的狗不想穿鞋
And his dog did not want to have shoes on.
‎因为牠一直这样…
He was doing that, like...
‎它是只小灵狗 ‎大部分时间都在颤抖
And it was a whippet situation, and they're shaky at the best of times.
‎我们不知道原因 是冷吗 ‎还是紧张 不知道
We don't know why. Are they cold? Are they nervous?
‎但牠就…一直这样
But it was like just... It was a lot.
‎对我的故事不重要 ‎但一直在我的周边
Now, it's not important to the story, but it was a lot in my periphery,
‎这点也让你明白
so I just want you to know.
‎附加压力
Added stress.
‎这是我朋友的破冰工具
Now, this was my, uh, friend's icebreaker.
‎我们从没见过 这是他的破冰方式 ‎他说 “你知道…
We'd never met. This was his icebreaker. He said, "Did you know...
it takes less muscles to smile than frown?"
‎笑比皱眉头用到的肌肉要少 ”
‎坐在观众席的男人大概觉得
The men in the audience are sitting there going,
‎“你遇到的只是个别事件”
"Oh, you've experienced an isolated incident."
‎坐在观众席的女人一定觉得 ‎“拜托 搞什么鬼”
And the women are sitting there going, "Oh, for fuck's sake."
‎而非二元性别的人会觉得 ‎“妳那天不顺吧 是吧 ”
And non-binary folk are like, "Is that a hard day for you? Is it?"
‎就破冰的话题来说 ‎这真是差劲透顶了
Now, as far as icebreakers go, it's a fucking shit one.
‎基本上他的意思是 ‎“你的脸不对 能换一张吗 ”
Basically what he's saying is, "Your face is wrong. Can you change it?"
‎真的 ‎就算我对他合理怀疑 是吧
Like, honestly. And even if I gave him the benefit of the doubt, right,
‎真的相信消耗能量是他的主要考量
and truly believed that energy consumption was his chief concern...
‎他看着我心想“她最好知道
That he was just looking at me, going, "If only she knew.
She could live her best life.
‎她就该享福了
‎要是她知道 她就能从日常获得更多”
She could get so much more out of her day if only she knew."
Like, even if I believed that,
‎就算我相信 问题是 ‎我既没笑也没有皱眉
the thing is, I was neither smiling nor frowning.
My face was neutral, which takes fuck all muscles.
‎我的脸毫无表情 ‎根本没用到肌肉
‎现在我大概明白我毫无表情时 ‎可能不太令人愉快
Now, I am aware that my neutral face is not particularly chipper.
‎我的确看起来像有个人 ‎反拿汤匙插进马铃薯里
Like, I do look like someone stabbed a potato with a spoon upside down.
Honestly, like...
‎真的
No muscles.
‎完全没用到肌肉
‎毫无表情
Neutral.
我就是一张臭脸 ‎如此而已
Now, I have resting bitch face. That's what it's called.
‎也就是大家所谓的婊子脸
That's what it's colloquially known as. Resting bitch face.
‎只有女人才有婊子脸
Only women have resting bitch face.
‎男人就脑袋思考着重要事情 ‎最好别打岔
Men simply have very important thoughts you'd best not interrupt them having.
‎真的 没人走到一个陌生男人面前
Honestly, no one has ever gone up to a man while he's a stranger and gone,
"Cheer up, love. It may never happen." No!
‎然后说“开心点 亲爱的 ‎可能根本不会发生” 从来没有
‎就破冰话题而言 这挺差劲的
As far as icebreakers go, that was a bit shit.
‎你知道我怎么回答
Do you know how I responded?
‎我开始皱眉
I started frowning.
‎我开始使用我之前
I started using muscles
根本不想使用的肌肉
I'd had no intention of using just moments earlier.
‎但他觉得好像非常顺利 ‎于是他又更向前迈进
But he thought it went very well, so he stepped the conversation up another notch,
‎他说“你的狗叫什么名字 ”经典
and he said, "What is your dog's name?" Classic.
And I responded by saying, "Doug."
我回答“道格”
‎因为我发现只有它惹麻烦时 ‎才会是道格拉斯
'Cause he's only Douglas when he's in trouble, I discovered.
‎当我说“道格”时 ‎这家伙有点反应过渡
Now, when I said, "Doug," this man's response was a little much.
‎他基本上… ‎在我说“道格”时 他就这样…
He's basically... I said, "Doug," and he's gone...
"Good one."
‎“好名字”
‎然后我说…
And I said...
"It's not."
‎“并不是”
I don't know why. I think I was still in Frown Land.
‎我不知道原因 ‎大概我还是眉头深锁
I've just gone, "It's not a good name."
‎我就说“并不是个好名字”
And he said, "It is."
‎然后他说“是好名字”
‎所以我说“不是”
So I said, "It's not."
‎这简直…这事真的发生了
So let's just... This is what's happening.
‎我在狗公园跟个陌生人吵
I'm having an argument with a stranger in the dog park
‎我狗的名字好不好
about whether or not my dog's name is good,
‎我并没有站在你假设的那一方
and I'm not on the side you'd assume I'd be on.
And his dog had shoes on.
‎而且他的狗穿鞋子
‎我们有更重要的事要谈
We had more important things to talk about.
Instead, we're going, "It's a bad name." "It's a good name."
‎结果我们却在那边说 ‎“坏名字” “好名字”
‎最后 他就说“听着
Eventually, he's like, "Look.
It's a good name, because Doug...
‎是个好名字 因为道格…
Dogs dig.
‎是狗 挖洞
‎道格（挖洞）”
Doug."
‎身为专业的喜剧演员 ‎当下我深感受辱
Now it was a singularly humiliating moment as a professional comedian
‎我自己的笑话 居然没想到
to have my own joke, that I hadn't even thought of,
‎结果还让别人解释
explained back to me.
‎好像我想过 只是忘记而已
As if I had thought of it, but just forgot.
‎像是我根本没注意到
Like, I didn't notice.
‎我养了道格超过一年
I'd had Doug for over a year.
都没想到牠的名字是个双关语
Hadn't fucking clocked that his name was a pun.
‎真丢脸
Humiliated.
‎所以我做了任何成年人会做的事 我撒谎
So I did what any reasonable, mature person would do. I lied.
I said, "No.
‎ 我说“不
‎它叫道格拉斯
I've-- His name's Douglas.
‎我以道格拉斯凹陷来替它命名
And I named him after the Pouch of Douglas,
‎我让你明白”
I will have you know."
‎他问“什么是道格拉斯凹陷 ”
And he said, "What is the Pouch of Douglas?"
‎这倒是问得很公平
And it's a fair question,
‎因为道格拉斯凹陷是个难解的情况
because the Pouch of Douglas is an obscure situation.
‎于是我解释了
So I explained.
‎我说“道格拉斯凹陷 ‎算是存在的潜在空间存在于
I said, "The Pouch of Douglas is a bit of potential space that exists,
and it's situated between the anal cavity...
‎女性肛门腔与…
‎子宫之间 女性生理的生育环境”
and the uterus in the female, biological sex reproductive environment."
‎在狗公园勒
At the dog park!
‎这家伙眼眨都不眨
And this guy did not blink.
‎他僵在那里
He's just frozen.
然后开始皱眉
And he started frowning.
‎他突然非常地努力
And... he was suddenly working very hard.
‎我接收到他那恐惧带着点排斥的表情
And I took that look of fear mingled with vague repulsion
and mistook it for genuine curiosity.
‎并且误以为是单纯好奇
And I thought, "This man wants to know more."
‎我想“这家伙求知欲挺强的”
‎于是我又解释 ‎“不在前面 也不在后面
So I explained, "It's neither front, nor back.
‎就在正中间
It's right in the middle.
‎在女性生殖器中立地区 ‎
It's in fanny neutral territory.
我们称之为阴部瑞士
We'll call it fanny Switzerland.
‎而且没有自己的入口” ‎我说的以为这样更清楚
And it doesn't have its own entrance," I said, as if that made it all better.
‎“像是 你不能… ‎根本到不了
"Like, you can't...  You can't just get to it.
Although, if you were to stick your thumb up the bum
‎虽然如果你把拇指塞进你的屁股
‎用手指把阴道撑高
and your finger up the relevant vagine...
and clap...
‎然后抠一下
‎差不多就在那里
that bit in there...
‎那就是你的道格拉斯凹陷处 ‎在那里面”
that's your Pouch of Douglas. In there."
‎在狗公园里勒
At the dog park!
'Cause it's not an actual thing. It's just...
‎因为这真的不是这样
It's a crawl space for emergencies. The best...
‎这是紧急逃生空间 ‎我最多…
‎我最多能这样解释
The best way I can explain it is this.
‎像是你有个行李箱而且想要打开来
You've got a suitcase and you want to open the suitcase.
‎你拉起拉链 沿着行李箱拉一圈
You take the zip all the way around the suitcase,
‎但当你要打开行李箱时却开不了
but when you go to open the suitcase, it does not open,
‎因为你没有拉真的拉链
because you have not used the zip zip.
‎而是拉到周围一圈的扩增拉链
You've used the funny zip, which does go all the way around the suitcase,
‎但打不开行李箱 骗了你
but it doesn't fucking open. It just mocks you.
So when you go to open the suitcase, it just does that...
‎所以当你打开行李箱 ‎就这样…
‎而你还没打开行李箱
And now, you have not opened the suitcase.
‎但你让里面的空间变大了
But what you've done is you've created a bit of extra space in there,
‎但你看不见 也摸不到
and you can't see it, and you can't access it.
‎但你知道存在在里面
But you know it's there.
‎那就是道格拉斯凹陷
That is the Pouch of Douglas.
‎非常感谢 我很开心
Thank you. I'm delighted.
‎我很开心你们喜欢 ‎我解释道格拉斯凹陷的方式
I'm delighted you enjoyed my explanation of the Pouch of Douglas,
‎因为我那位狗公园的朋友不爱
because my friend at the dog park did not.
‎我仍旧无法释怀 ‎因为我体内有东西
I just still can't get over that there's something inside of me,
‎尤其在我身体里那特别的部位
in a very particular part of my body...
‎叫做道格拉斯凹陷
called the Pouch of Douglas.
‎超奇怪 也不算好
It's fucking weird, borderline not okay.
‎但也提醒我们生活在一个
But it is also a reminder that we do live in a world
‎一切由男人命名的世界里
where everything has been named by men.
‎所有一切
Everything.
‎一切的一切
‎那是以一位男性医师 ‎詹姆斯道格拉斯而命名
And that was named after a man. Dr. James Douglas,
‎他是一位十八世纪的苏格兰助产男士
who was an 18th century Scottish man midwife.
‎真是个令人很不“苏湖”的人口统计
What an uncomfortable collection of demographics that is.
‎别把你领英档案的标题写成这个
Like, do not headline your LinkedIn with that.
这是个错误
That is a mistake.
It was named after Dr. James Douglas, because apparently he found it first.
‎以詹姆斯道格拉斯医师来命名 ‎显然是他最先发现的
‎那天真精彩 ‎他那天应该过得很精彩
What a day. What a day he must have been having.
‎对个女尸临检
Just rummaging around a lady cadaver.
‎检查检查 当时的嗜好不同
Rummage, rummage. Hobbies were different then.
‎他肯定找到增大拉链
He must have just found her funny zip,
‎然后看到它存在那里 ‎一个空间 没有名字
and then saw it sitting there, all void, no name.
‎当下詹姆斯道格拉斯医师 ‎肯定想到“这就是了
At which point, Dr. James Douglas must have thought, "Well, this is it.
‎这是我成为传奇的机会”
- -This is my shot at legacy."
‎老实说 这老是让我惊异不已
Honestly, it just never ceases to amaze me
‎小家伙要怎么做 ‎才能留名青史
how little men have to do in order to be remembered.
‎他发现了个“没什么” ‎然后宣称是他的
He found a "not thing" and called dibs.
‎要是女人参与命名的话
We would live in a very different world
‎我们的世界将会非常不一样
if women had participated in the naming of things.
Like, do you fellows honestly believe you'd have balls
‎你们各位真的相信 ‎如果让女人参与那场会议
‎你们会有球球吗
if women had been at that meeting?
‎才不会 因为是这样的
No. 'Cause here's the thing.
‎女人不会把你们的睪丸 ‎当成运动或是比赛
Women don't think of your testicles as a sport or a game.
‎你们喜欢玩 ‎这完全跟我们无关
You like to play with them. That is your bag and your bag alone.
-Cool story. -
‎这故事很酷吧
‎但如果我们叫做 ‎“凯伦双手握不住” 你们觉得呢
But how would you like it if we'd have given you "Karen's handful?"
‎你们究竟喜欢不喜欢
How the fuck would you like that?
‎让个老女人整天抓着你的腰内肉
Just having an olde woman with a grip around your tenderloins all fucking day.
‎你们会喜欢吗
How would you like that?
‎抱歉 我显然不是专家 ‎这怎么回事
I'm so sorry. I'm clearly not an expert. What is this?
‎非常抱歉
- -I am sorry.
‎在我想象里面 ‎凯伦是个牵线木偶
I think, in my mind's eye, Karen is a marionette. Just...
‎“这球球… ”
"What do balls...?"
‎我得去看医生
I had to see a doctor...
‎好久以前的事了
Uh, this is a while ago.
‎因为我的道格拉斯环境 ‎出了点问题
Um... 'Cause I had some issues with my Douglas environment,
‎非常广义的说来
very broadly speaking.
‎我的家医不在 我得看她的代班
And my regular doctor was away, so I was seeing her replacement.
‎那位代班医师
Uh, now, the replacement doctor
要是让我选 ‎我绝对不会选
was not a doctor I would ever have chosen for myself.
‎我们不太对盘 一开始就不太好
We weren't a good match. We didn't get along from the get-go.
‎他是目中无人的混球
He was a fucking arrogant asshole.
‎当然他绝对也是位合格的医师
I mean, he was a qualified doctor as well. Yes, absolutely.
‎那是张有很多交叉的维恩图
But that is a Venn diagram with a lot of crossover.
‎就把他称为混帐饼干医师
We're going to call him Dr. Dick Biscuit.
‎好的 来啦
Okay, there it is.
‎在不经过任何检查后 ‎混帐饼干医师决定
Now, Dr. Dick Biscuit decided, after running no tests,
‎我道格拉斯不适症的解决方式…
that the solution to my Douglas malaise...
‎就是我该继续吃那个药（避孕药）
was that I should go on the pill.
‎药 男人命名一切 ‎还有更多的证据
The pill. There's more proof men have named all the things.
‎“那个药” 这很模糊吧
"The pill." That's a bit fucking vague, isn't it?
‎“医生 你大多开的处方签‎都叫做药”
"Most things you prescribe, Doctor, could be called a pill."
‎他说“是的 但这是那个药”
He's like, "Yes, but this is the pill. The pill."
It sounds like there's just a giant pill in the town square
‎听起来就象是小镇广场上 ‎有一颗巨大的药
‎我们都冲上去吃 ‎还喊着“今天星期一”
we all scurry out and nibble on, "Mmm, it's Monday."
‎“有什么效用 ” ‎“巫术 闭嘴 叫药就行了”
"What does it do?" "Witchcraft. Shut up. Call it a pill."
‎我对混帐饼干医师说 ‎“听着 我不想吃药
I said to Dr. Dick Biscuit, "Look, I don't want to take the pill.
‎我之前服过药 而药物让我有自杀的念头”
I've been on the pill before and the pill tends to give me suicidal ideation."
‎你以为我创伤都讲光了
[chuckles] You thought I was all out of trauma.
‎混帐饼干医师不喜欢我提这件事
Now, Dr. Dick Biscuit didn't enjoy me bringing that to the table.
‎这次诊断是诊断我的身体
The table being a consultation about my body.
‎他敬谢不敏
He's like, "No. No, thank you very much."
And do you know what he did? He shushed me.
‎你知道他做了什么 ‎他叫我闭嘴
He said, "You will do well to listen to me."
‎他说“你乖乖听我的话做”
It was our first fight.
‎这是我们第一次的争执
‎我做了在冲突中 ‎我都会做的事情
And I did what I always do in a bit of conflict.
‎我说了个笑话 这是我的笑话
I made a joke. This was my joke.
‎我说“与其吃药 ‎不如切除我的子宫吧”
I said, "Instead of going on the pill, how about I have a hysterectomy?"
‎是啊 你就听懂了 ‎我不知道他为何听不懂
Yep, you get it. I don't know why he didn't get it.
‎就笑话来说 这算是经典
As far as jokes go, that's a classic.
-I can't... -
‎我想不出
‎不是笑话的内容
think of a context where that wouldn't be a joke.
像是我究竟有什么本事 ‎能控制我的身体
Like, on what planet would I have control over my own body?
‎起码这里不行
Not this one.
‎显然这是个笑话
So clearly, it's a joke.
‎而且应该也很清楚 ‎因为我用玩笑词
And also, it should have been clear, because I used jokey words.
‎我并没有用正式的词汇
I didn't use formal terminology.
I did not say, "Hysterectomy."
‎我没说“子宫切除术”
‎我当时说的是“我们何不干脆整组拿掉好了 ”
What I said was, "Why don't we just whip out the whole kit and caboodle?"
‎如果这还不清楚是说笑 ‎我还接着说
Then, if that wasn't clear enough I was joking, I followed it up with,
"Besides, I've heard decluttering is in fashion, Doctor.
‎“而且我听说现在很流行清除多余物品 医师
‎这并不会带来生活乐趣”
And this does not spark joy."
‎感谢 我很开心
Thank you. I'm delighted.
‎我很开心你们都喜欢这个笑话
I'm delighted you enjoyed that joke.
‎因为混帐饼干医生不喜欢
Because Dr. Dick Biscuit did not.
‎他听不懂我的笑话
He did not get my joke.
‎于是我并不明白他的慈悲
And so, I did not get his humanity.
‎于是情况开始转为激烈 ‎他就开始对我大吼
And things just escalated from there, and he just began shouting at me.
‎然后他就展开言语攻击
Right? And when he just fully laid into me,
然后我开始哭
at which point I began to cry,
‎然后混帐饼干医师 ‎把我的痛苦当证据
and then Dr. Dick Biscuit took my distress as proof...
‎证明他诊断正确
his diagnosis was correct.
‎显然我荷尔蒙失调
Clearly, I was hormonal.
‎典型回避 混帐饼干
Classic cop-out, Dick Biscuit.
‎我的老天
Fuck me.
‎男人说女人荷尔蒙失调
Men calling women hormonal.
Pretty much it's the number one hobby of mankind of all time.
‎大概是人类有史以来的第一个习惯
‎就像男人可以说女人荷尔蒙失调
Like, a man is allowed to call a woman hormonal
‎只要女人说或是做了 ‎男人意料之外的事情时
just whenever a woman says or does something a man failed to predict.
That's it.
‎就这样
‎像是“我根本没想到会这样
It's like, "I wasn't expecting that,
‎显然你的里面乱七八糟
so, clearly, you're just a cluster fuck of internalized chaos
‎你注定就是个婊子”
you make up to be a bitch."
‎像是男人没有荷尔蒙 ‎而说女人是荷尔蒙失调
Like, men call women hormonal as if men don't have hormones.
‎这就是让我不爽的地方
That's the bit that shits me.
‎因为根据最新消息 兄弟 ‎你也有荷尔蒙
Because newsflash, fellas, you've got hormones.
‎因为有时候你会暴躁
And sometimes you get testy.
‎是啊 你就会
Yeah, you do.
‎有时候 凯伦用力捏一下
Sometimes Karen gives it a bit of a squeeze...
‎你就生气
and you get upset.
‎很公平 你也是人 ‎我们大家都会
And fair enough, you're only human. Happens to the best of us.
‎众人皆知我在满月的时候 ‎想要吃一口黑巧克力
Look, I've been known to want to nibble a bit of dark chocolate on a full moon.
我也不懂
I don't know.
‎巫术
- -Witchcraft.
‎但我绝不会对门出拳
But I've never had to punch a door.
‎我们都有自己的问题 兄弟
So we all have our things, fellas.
Like, honestly, what do you think "boys will be boys" means...
‎老实说 你以为“男生永远长不大”是什么意思
‎要是男人擅长中和荷尔蒙的话
if men are so good at neutralizing their hormones?
‎这不是性侵的方便借口
Like, it's not the convenient alibi for sexual assault
‎好多人好喜欢拿这个当作借口
that so many people are so desperate for it to mean.
‎“男孩永远长不大”什么意思
Know what "boys will be boys" means?
‎这表示还没让小子准备好 ‎面对这个世界
It means we are not preparing our boys for the real world.
‎这表示我们很清楚
It means we know.
‎我们清楚男孩子的贺尔蒙不受控
We know that boys are at the mercy of their hormones.
‎我们只是人文学上 ‎无法让他们对自己行为负责
We're just culturally incapable of holding them accountable for their actions,
‎所以我们让女人来负责
so we hold women accountable.
‎住手
Stop it!
‎这是圈套 你们这些白痴 ‎这是套 搁着就好
It's bait, you fucking idiots. It's bait. Leave it!
‎不要对号入座
It's not for you.
‎这不是集会
It's not a rally.
‎我靠
Fuck.
‎每次我这么做 我就觉得 ‎我在圈套周围走一圈
Every time I do that, I feel like I've got to walk around the bait.
‎我不需要我的贺尔蒙不理性
Look, I don't need my hormones to be unreasonable.
‎我只是想让男人了解这件事
I would just love men to know that.
‎我不需要…
Like, I don't need...
我可以就因为我不想 ‎而无理取闹
I can just be unreasonable 'cause I don't wanna.
‎我有很多我所谓的 ‎“河豚鱼时刻” 对吧
I have plenty of what I call "puffer fish moments." Right?
‎你知道河豚鱼
You know puffer fish?
那些鱼被惊动 ‎就会这样 “这就是解决之道”
Those fish that get startled and go, "Oh, this is a solution."
‎实则不然
It's not.
‎就是这样 ‎我充满了这种无能的愤怒
That's what happens. I get filled with this impotent fury
‎我对我所生气的事情 ‎根本束手无策
and I can't do anything about whatever it is I'm angry about,
所以我就会…
because I'm just like... [groaning]
‎“如果你吃我 我就会搞死你 ‎否则我就在这里”
"If you eat me, I'll fuck you up, but otherwise I'm just over here."
‎但让我变成河豚鱼只是一些小事
And it's only little things that'll set the puffer fish off.
‎鸡毛蒜皮的事 ‎不是大事 像是原始人饮食法
Little things. Not the big picture. Little things, like the paleo diet.
‎别对我鬼扯这东西
Don't even look sideways at me with that shit.
‎因为我的反应绝对失控
- -Because my response is out of control.
‎不成比例
It's disproportionate.
‎有人会很无辜的说“我在用原始人饮食法减肥”
Someone will just innocently say, "I'm on the paleo," and I'll go,
我大叫“是吗 ”
[yells] "Are you?
‎首先，我不在乎 ‎再来，你口很臭
First of all, I don't care. Two, your breath stinks.
‎拜托吃点纤维好嘛
Eat some fucking fiber, for fuck's sake.
‎第三 我们也不知道他吃了什么
Three, we don't know what they ate.
‎我们根本不知道 ‎真正的原始人吃什么
We have no clue what paleolithic humans actually ate.
But we are dead certain they didn't eat cauliflower popcorn, you prick!"
‎但打死我们也不相信 ‎他们吃花椰菜爆米花 你这混蛋
‎你瞧 这跟我月经有没有来 ‎根本没有关系
And, you see, it doesn't matter where on my cycle I am.
‎同样愤怒
Same rage.
‎《威利在哪里 》则是另一个
Where's Waldo? is another one.
‎去他的
[scoffs] Fuck him.
‎为什么是沃里 为什么
Because why is Waldo? Why? Why?
‎为何我们浪费这么多时间
Why have we wasted so many hours
‎好几代的儿时来找那个混球
out of the lives of generations of children looking for that prick?
‎因为你不断地寻找 ‎寻找算是投入
Because you look and look, and looking is an investment.
‎你开始在乎 然后你开始担心 ‎
You're caring, and then you start to worry.
“我希望他没事”
"I hope he's okay."
‎然后你找到他 一切都不重要了 ‎都不重要了
And then you find him and nothing is ever the matter. Ever!
‎他只是在度假 相当享受人生
He's only ever on holiday, having quite a nice time of it.
‎去你的 沃里
Fuck you, Waldo!
‎他该跟我们其他人一样找到自己
He should have to find himself, like the rest of us have to.
‎真的
Honestly.
‎如果你想看白人男性优越的童书模板
If you want to see a children's book illustration of white male privilege,
‎那个家伙绝对是
it is that guy.
‎因为这家伙以逸待劳
Because here is a man who makes no effort.
‎完全不出力帮自己
No effort to help himself,
‎然后完全希望地球上的每个人
yet fully expects everybody on Earth
‎一直以来在乎他究竟在哪里
to give a shit about his whereabouts at all times.
Just change your ugly fucking jumper, mate.
‎换一下你丑毙了的套头衫 兄弟
‎老实说 那愤怒就跟 ‎月亮和潮水起伏有关了
To be honest, that one does fluctuate depending on the moon and the tides.
‎但老实说 真是浪费我的情绪资源
But ultimately, what a waste of my emotional resources.
‎我同时也浪费在《忍者龟》上头
I also waste them on the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
‎问题大了
[popping sound] Big issue.
‎都是多纳泰罗 告诉你原因
It's Donatello. I'll tell you why.
‎要是你不知道
Now, if you didn't know,
忍者龟是街头帮派
the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles are a street gang,
‎奇怪的是 我对这没意见
and, weirdly, that is not my issue.
‎是漫画、电视影集 ‎也改编成电影
It's a comic book, television, film franchise
‎目标观众群大概就是青少年
and the target demographic for it is pretty much young boys.
‎忍者龟各个都有名字
Now, the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles have names.
‎米开朗基罗、李奥纳多、拉斐尔 ‎以及多纳泰罗
They are Michelangelo, Leonardo, Raphael, and Donatello.
‎他们是以文艺复兴艺术家来命名
They are named after Renaissance artists.
Because nothing says frescoes like nunchucks. Am I right?
‎因为没有说壁画像双截棍 ‎对吧
‎我说错了
I'm not right.
‎文艺复兴有意思的地方是
Now, the interesting thing about the Renaissance,
‎我们普遍了解的文艺复兴
what we popularly understand as the Renaissance
‎是意大利文艺复兴全盛时期 ‎非常短暂的艺术运动
is the Italian High Renaissance, and that was a very short art movement.
‎二十年 没了
Twenty years, over.
‎从1500年到1520年 就这样
It went from 1500 to 1520. Done.
‎米开朗基罗、李奥纳多、拉斐尔
Now, Michelangelo, Leonardo, Raphael,
‎这二十年都是他们艺术上颠峰的状态
all at the height of their artistic prowess during those 20 years.
‎多纳泰罗 惨了
Donatello, oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no. He was dead.
‎惨了 他死了
‎他1465年就死了
Dead by 1465.
‎他根本就不是街头帮派份子的一员
[yelling] He does not belong in their street gang!
‎他死了
He's dead!
‎你知道谁才属于那街头帮派吗
Do you know who belongs in that street gang?
‎提香 他才是正宗
Titian. By rights, it should be Titian.
‎你知道为何提香...
Do you know why Titian...
‎你知道为何提香不在那街头帮派里面
Do you know why Titian is not in that street gang?
‎因为那电视节目的目标族群
Because the target demographic of that television show
‎没有办法接受名字开头为提（奶子）
could not handle a name that begins with "tit"
‎就因为他们天杀的荷尔蒙
because of their fucking hormones.
‎我们还没让男孩子准备好 ‎面对真实世界
We are not preparing our boys for the real world.
‎或是男人写的历史 ‎这就奇了吧
Or history, which they wrote. Weird.
‎而且他们是陆龟
And they're tortoises.
‎他们不是海龟
They are not turtles!
‎他们是陆龟
- -They are tortoises.
‎陆龟是脚 海龟是蹼
Tortoises are the clomp, clomps. Turtles are the flip, flips.
‎我明白…
-Now, I understand... -
‎我明白他们突变 我懂
I understand that they're mutants. I get it.
‎但他们用双截棍
But they are using nunchucks.
‎这表示他们得要具备 ‎某些陆地的灵巧性
This means they need to have some terrestrial dexterity experience,
‎而且这还不够
and this is not enough!
‎我们没准备好让男孩子们 ‎面对真实世界
We are not preparing our boys for the real world.
‎要是他们去了加拉巴哥群岛呢 ‎屎了
What if they went to the Galapagos? Fucked.
‎我最近的河豚时刻爆发…
My most recent puffer fish...
‎是在跟一个家伙交谈
was during a conversation with this bloke
‎他想告诉我高尔夫不算是运动
who was trying to tell me that golf is not a sport...
‎因为对你的心血管系统 ‎没有造成压力
because it doesn't put stress on your cardiovascular system.
‎这不是挺没意思的吗
Isn't that not interesting?
‎不管你怎么转 无聊
Doesn't matter how you spin it. Dull.
‎情况继续恶化 因为他讲个没完
And it gets worse, because he kept talking.
‎他说“如果你参加一个
He said, "If you're participating in something
‎对于心血管系统没有压力的事
and it doesn't put stress on your cardiovascular system,
‎就不算是运动
you're not participating in a sport.
‎你只是在玩游戏”
You're merely playing a game."
‎那场对话让我超生气
And that conversation made me so fucking angry,
‎感觉挺像运动的
it felt like a sport.
‎我希望这里没人说“终于
Now, I hope nobody's in here, just going, "Finally, oh.
‎这里有人捍卫高尔夫的名誉”
Someone here to defend golf's honor."
‎这里绝对没有这种事
That is not what's happening here.
‎事实上 我希望高尔夫难过
In fact, I hope golf is sad.
‎我希望高尔夫满腹牢骚
I hope golf is all sooky la la,
‎因为我对高尔夫 ‎说多痛恨就有多痛恨
'cause I fucking hate golf with all the reasonable rage I can muster.
‎土地、时间、水资源的巨大浪费
What a monumental waste of land, time, and water.
‎搞什么鬼
For fuck's sake.
‎真的
- -Honestly.
‎有家室的男人还打高尔夫
Men who have families and play golf
‎简直是蠢蛋
are cunts.
‎你没时间 兄弟 你有个家庭
You don't have time, fellas. You've got a family.
‎没有空闲的六小时 ‎跟你的朋友在公园漫步
Not a spare six hours to just waltz around a park with your mates
‎让你的女人付出一切免费的劳力
while your womenfolk do unpaid labor!
‎成熟点
Grow up!
‎还有更多证据证明一切由男人命名
There's more proof men have named all the things.
‎你骂别人最难听的是什么
What's the worst thing you can call someone?
‎鲍鱼
Cunt.
‎这说的是女人的阴道 ‎我不能忍受
It's a reference to female genitalia, and I won't have it.
‎我说阴道的时候 ‎真的是指阴道
When I use the C-word, I mean it.
‎我认为这是你骂人最难听的话
I mean it to be the worst thing you can call someone,
‎但我不会扯上我自己的身理 ‎或是任何人的身理
but I don't associate it with my own biology or anybody's biology.
‎你知道我说阴道时会想到什么
Do you know what I see in my mind's eye when I use the C-word?
‎真正的高尔夫球手
A literal golfer.
‎一个有钱的白人大块头佬 ‎穿着斜纹布裤 戴一支手套
Just a rich, white chump in chinos and one glove.
‎十足的白痴
What a cunt.
Honestly, it cannot be a coincidence that they're called cunt-ry clubs.
‎老实说 会叫做老土（乡村）俱乐部 ‎一点也不奇怪
‎拜托
Come on.
I'll tell you what, my... my last show, Nanette,
‎跟你们说 我上个节目《娜娜》
‎让很多人像河豚爆怒
gave a lot of people the puffer fish.
Like, pfff, you know you've made it.
‎像是你明白你做到了
‎我说很多人 表示不只是男人
And I say people, but it was only men.
‎标签“并非都是男人” 好吗
Hashtag "not all men." Okay?
‎当然 不全都是男人
Of course, it's not all men.
‎从来就不全是男的
It's never been all men.
‎一般说来 真的只有 ‎使用那标签的人
Generally speaking, it's really only the men who use that hashtag.
‎就是他们
-They're the ones. -
‎你知道男人 意味着“我”
You know, men, pronounced "me."
‎他们挺身而出
You know, they're the ones who go out of their way
‎告诉我《娜娜》不是喜剧
to let me know that Nanette was not comedy.
‎“因为节目里每个梗都没让我笑出来”
"Because it didn't make me laugh every step of the way."
‎首先 很好
First of all, good.
‎要是那节目让你从头笑到尾 ‎你究竟有什么毛病
If that show made you laugh all the way through, what the fuck is wrong with you?
‎再来 我把笑话龙头关掉
Secondly, yes, I turned the laugh tap off myself.
‎这是我的决定 我坚持这点
It was a decision. I stand by it.
‎不是我到了节目一半 ‎觉得“惨了 我没笑话可说
It's not like I got halfway through and thought, "Fuck, I'm out of jokes.
‎决定说个悲伤故事”
I'll tell a sad story. I hope anyone won't notice."
‎我比任何人清楚 我在《娜娜》里 ‎所表演的技术上而言不算喜剧
I know better than anyone that what I did with Nanette was not technically comedy.
‎我也不是他妈的白痴
But I'm also not a fucking idiot.
‎我要那节目有观众 一批广大的观众
I wanted that show to have an audience, and a broad audience,
‎如果那表示我得骗人
and if that meant I had to trick people...
‎称之为喜剧…
by calling it comedy...
‎技术上而言就是笑话
that's technically a joke.
‎但我得说…
But I have to say...
‎我得说 一个不好笑的笑话 ‎让许多男人打从心底愤怒
I have to say, a bad joke made so many men so viscerally angry
‎我很惊讶没人控诉我写运动 真的
I'm surprised nobody accused me of writing a sport, honestly.
这...
-It... -
‎首先 我不在乎 是吧
Look, first of all, it doesn't bother me. Right?
‎这并不会困扰我
This doesn't bother me. Look, look.
‎我还拿着大声的麦克风 ‎我没有感到威胁
I've still got the loud stick. I don't feel threatened.
‎事实上 我喜欢那种痛恨
In fact, I-I like the hate.
‎死亡威胁靠边站 很有趣 ‎好好吃
Death threats aside, it's fun. Nom, nom, nom.
‎对吧 问题是每当我‎像河豚爆怒时
Right? But the thing is, whenever I have a puffer fish...
‎我总是开始假设
I always work under the assumption
‎问题大部分在我 对吧
that the problem is mostly me, right? If I'm like... [popping sound]
‎如果我这样… ‎感觉就不容易好好开始说话
It just doesn't seem like a good place to start a dialog.
‎我从没写信给多纳泰罗或是沃里
I have never written a letter to Donatello or Waldo.
‎没必要 一个死了 ‎一个从不回家
Like, no point. One's dead and one's never home.
‎但仍然 我…
But still, I just...
‎从没想过
Wouldn't occur to me.
‎但今天 我还收到男人 ‎直接在我推特上留言
But to this day, I still get men sliding into my DMs
‎让我知道 全部都大写 ‎
to let me know, in all caps,
说他们从没听过我
[loudly] that they've never heard of me.
‎这是个谜
It's a riddle.
‎他们怎么知道
How do they know?
‎我没办法体悟到羞辱 ‎我懂他们非常想让我感受到
Look, I can't experience the humiliation I know they're so desperate for me to feel
‎因为我没办法不担心他们
because I can't help but feel worried for them.
‎因为这样人生难过
Because that's a tough life.
‎如果新事物如此痛苦…
If new things are so painful...
‎这就是学习障碍了
Ow. They.... That's a learning difficulty.
Imagine school for someone like that.
‎想象一下 学校里有那种人
Long division.
‎长除法
‎“我他妈的从没听过”
[yells] "I've never fucking heard of it!"
‎我被控诉做过所有不道德的事情 ‎而非喜剧
I got accused of doing all sorts of nefarious things in lieu of comedy.
‎真的 像是独白
I really did. Like a monologue.
‎如果是真的 那还真是个怪兽
What a monster, if true.
‎一场受崇拜的TED演讲
A glorified TED Talk. Uh-oh.
‎独女秀
A one-woman show.
‎说教 天杀的说教
A lecture. A fucking lecture. Can you believe that one?
‎你相信吗 放肆地说教
The cheek of that one. A lecture.
‎《娜娜》不是说教 也不是独白
Nanette was not a fucking lecture. It wasn't a monologue either.
‎又不是我坐在板凳上 ‎在舞台灯下像条目瞪口呆的鲱鲤
It wasn't like I was sitting on a stool like a stunned mullet in a spotlight.
‎不是天杀的独白
It wasn't a fucking monologue.
‎受崇拜的TED演讲 ‎为何他们要崇拜
And a glorified TED Talk? Why do they need glorifying?
‎他们根本就很好
They are fine.
‎独女秀
And a one-woman show?
‎认真 福尔摩斯
No shit, Sherlock!
‎也不是天杀的说教
And it wasn't a fucking lecture.
‎你想听说教 我就对你说教
You want a lecture? I'll give you a fucking lecture.
‎这才是说教
This is a lecture!
‎关于文艺复兴事实上
Now, there is some debate...
as to when the High Renaissance actually began.
‎从何时开始 其实有些争论
‎有人说1940年
Some put it at 1490,
‎但有些人则说是1500年开始
while others argue it began in 1500.
‎不论哪一个 多纳泰罗早死透了
Either way, Donatello was fucking dead.
‎回到16世纪 凯伦的手非常冰
Back in the 16th century, Karen had very, very cold hands.
‎暖个手 小凯 快点
Give them a rub, Kaz. Come on.
‎这是拉斐尔的《雅典学院》
Now, this is Raphael's School of Athens.
‎这就是拉斐尔非常好心地画出
This is where Raphael has so kindly painted all the men
‎命名所有一切的男人
who named all of the things.
‎现在…
-Now... -
‎严格说来 ‎这些不是拉斐尔的当代人物
strictly speaking, these are not Raphael's contemporaries,
‎虽然他用了他们的相似之处
although he has used their likeness.
‎基本上这些是古希腊人物
But basically, these are the ancient Greeks,
‎拉斐尔画这画的时候 ‎所有的希腊人早就死透了
and, by the time Raphael painted this, all the Greeks were dead.
‎不是所有希腊人 ‎我非常抱歉
Not all the Greeks. I am so sorry.
‎今天世界上仍有许多 ‎活着并且蓬勃的希腊人
There are still a lot of Greeks alive and thriving in the world today.
‎哈啰 欢迎
Hello and welcome.
‎不是的 只有古代希腊人 ‎他们全都死光了
No, just the ancient Greeks. They are all dead.
They lived on a busy road. It was built by the ancient Romans.
‎他们住在由古罗马人 ‎建造的繁忙街道上
‎我们这儿有谁呢 ‎有毕达哥拉斯
Now, who have we got here? We've got Pythagoras.
‎他忙着命名所有三角形
He's busy naming all the triangles.
‎这锐角（可爱）
That's acute one.
‎还有苏格拉底
You've got Socrates here.
‎他滚了一下 典型的苏格拉底
He took a bit of a tumble. Classic Socrates.
‎非常善于思考 却经常绊倒 ‎起来 芝麻叶兄弟
Good with the thoughts, shit with the walk. Get up, mate. Arugula.
‎所有男人忙着…
Now, what were the women doing
‎命名一切的大事时 ‎女人都在干嘛呢
while all the men were doing the very important naming of all the things?
‎就我研究的资料显示
From my research, what I gather,
‎女人通常三个一组站在旁边 裸体
women were generally standing around in groups of three, naked,
‎等着男人命名一切事物
just waiting for men to name all of the things.
‎你可以看见中央的这位
You can see it happening with this central figure.
‎她说“妳手里拿着什么 凯伦 ”
She's saying, "What have you got in your hand there, Karen?"
‎“只是一些小东西”
"Oh, just a couple of bits and bobs."
‎女人只是拿着东西 等着 ‎希望东西没有毒
Women were just holding things. Just waiting, hoping it wasn't poisonous.
‎等着男人命名一切
Waiting for men to name the things.
‎这是在床被命名之前画的
This was painted before beds were named.
‎你可以看到女人非常想要整理床铺
You can see women desperately trying to make the beds,
‎无可奈何地把床单抛在树上
just flinging the linen into the trees willy-nilly.
‎说着“我不知道 搭个城堡好了
Just going, "Oh, I don't know. Mm, let's just build a fort.
‎来搭个漂亮的城堡
We'll make it a fancy fort.
‎太棒了 我们搭好城堡了”
Yay, we finished the fort!"
‎三人在森林里裸体跳舞
Dancing naked in groups of three in the forest
‎一直以来都是女人的第一嗜好
is the number one hobby of women of all time.
‎我们超爱的吧
And don't we just love it.
‎这不是你所听过最安全的事 ‎我们好爱
Isn't that the safest thing you've ever heard of? Oh, we love it.
‎这可看起来象是个自由自在 ‎在林子里无拘无束嬉闹
Now, this might just look like a footloose,
‎还是国定假日 没有问题
fancy-free frolic in the forest on a bank holiday, no drama.
‎我再请你看看这一群
But let me draw your attention to this group here.
‎单纯玩乐的话 显然太紧了
That is too tight for fun times alone.
‎这意味着紧张
It suggests tension.
‎发生什么事
- -What has happened?
有人提到原始人饮食法
Has someone mentioned the paleo?
‎没有
-No. -
‎这里是说中间这位女士发现
What has happened is this central figure here
‎这块布 纱布
has realized that this bit of cloth, this waft of gauze,
‎这可能的城堡布…
this potential fort, if you will...
‎一路上来到她的肛门
has made its way so far up her clacker...
‎一路上来到她的肛门 ‎把她小妹妹遮住
So far up her clacker, it has both fannies covered.
‎她超生气
And she is upset.
‎值得此刻说明的是
Now, it's worth pointing out, at this juncture,
‎这不是照片
that this is not a photograph.
‎这不是一张意外的照片
-This is not an accidental photograph... -
‎拍下不幸的时刻 尴尬
taken of an unfortunate moment. Awkward.
‎不 这是一张画
No, what this is, is a painting.
‎也就是说这是…
Which makes this...
‎决定下的产物
[yells] a decision!
‎这是男人的决定而且还在上面花时间
It's a decision that a man made and spent time on.
‎我有自闭症
I have autism.
‎一点点的独白
It's a tiny monologue.
‎最近才诊断出来 仅四年前而已
I was very late diagnosed. Only four years ago.
‎四年前诊断出来
Diagnosed four years ago.
‎但我先自我诊断出来
But I-I self-diagnosed first,
‎找专家前非常棒的方法
which is a great way to approach any specialist.
‎他们很喜欢
Ooh, they love it. Oh.
‎他们说“多告诉我一点你的想法”
They say, "Tell me more about what you think."
‎我甚至想到自我诊断的唯一理由
But the only reason I even thought to self-diagnose
‎因为大家不断告诉我
was because people kept telling me.
It was usually after a show.
‎通常都是节目后
‎就会有人上来跟我说 ‎“我觉得你有自闭症”
People would just come up to me and say, "I think you have autism."
‎老实说我生命里每一位 ‎对我这么做的人
To be fair to every single person that's ever done that to me in my life,
‎我认为他们全都在这光谱范围内
I think they were all on the spectrum.
‎因为这叫做物以类聚
Because that's how we roll.
Pretty much, it's like, "I have a piece of information you seem to be missing.
‎就好像是“我有你好像没有的信息”
‎不管你有没有心理准备 ‎我还是告诉你吧
You may or may not be ready to hear this information,
‎因为知识就是力量
but I'll tell you, because knowledge is power,
无知是牢笼 ‎情绪可以慢慢处理
ignorance is a cage. and feelings can be dealt with.
‎祝你顺心了”
I bid you good day."
‎我的问题在于我不了解自闭症
My issue was I didn't understand enough about autism
‎来明白我怎么会有自闭症
to understand how I could have autism.
‎因为我们可能对自闭症的了解
Because what we popularly understand autism to be
‎就是好像只有影响 ‎非常喜欢数学的小男孩
is just something that only affects young boys that like maths a lot.
‎到今天为止 这些条件我身上都没有
And, to this day, neither of those things apply to me.
‎所以大家来跟我说 ‎“我想你有自闭症”
So people would tell me, "I think you have autism."
‎我的反应是 ‎“我不懂你怎么会这么想”
I'm like, "I don't understand how you got that."
‎当然我打过疫苗 除此外…
I mean, sure I've been vaccinated, but other than that...
欧，嘿!
Oh, hey!
‎来了
Here it is. Oh.
‎你们自己系好了
Strap yourselves in.
‎在所有自闭症相关的有毒迷思中 ‎这个应该是摆在第一位
Of all the toxic myths about autism, that's got to be right up the top.
‎至少不是因为我们知道
Not least because we know...
‎疫苗不会引发自闭症
[chuckles] that vaccinations do not cause autism.
‎你知道什么才会引发自闭症
Do you know what causes autism?
‎不 鬼才知道
No. You fucking don't.
-And if... -
‎而且如果…
‎如果你真的以为你知道
If you honestly think you do,
‎那就是你的自信让你傻了
your confidence is making you stupid.
‎我也知道我说什么也不能
Now, I also know that there's nothing I can say
‎改变反疫苗人士的心态
that can change an anti-vaxxer's mind.
‎我很清楚 ‎因为封闭的心灵不是如此运作
I know that, because that's not how closed minds work.
‎根本没在运作
They don't work.
‎打烊了 对吧
They're closed for business. Right?
‎要打开封闭的心灵 必须由内部执行
So... like, to open a closed mind, it has to be an inside job.
‎所以我很清楚我没办法 ‎改变反疫苗人士的心态
So I know there's nothing I can do that'll change an anti-vaxxer's mind.
I'm gonna have a go anyway. Gonna have a go.
‎但我还是继续说吧
‎因为我的理论是 说他们心灵封闭
Because my theory is, by accusing them of having a closed mind,
‎他们肯定说“不 我才没有” ‎然后我就能进去了
they'll be reactive and go, "No, I don't," and I'll get in.
‎而且现场这里绝对有反疫苗人士
And there will be anti-vaxxers in this room. Absolutely.
‎别自己对号入座 千万不要 ‎这不是重点
Do not identify yourselves. Do not. That is not what's happening here.
‎你们为数众多
You are outnumbered.
‎我知道你喜欢刻意操弄统计
And I know you like to willfully manipulate statistics,
‎但这根本就不是在说你
but this is even beyond you.
‎更何况…
And also...
‎现场的确有反疫苗人士 绝对没错
And there will be anti-vaxxers in this room, make no mistake,
‎因为我的核心人口统计 ‎是富有白人符合资格的女性
because my core demographic is rich, white, entitled women,
‎而且是一张很多交错的维恩图
and that is a Venn diagram with a lot of crossover.
‎但如果你是反疫苗人士
But if you are an anti-vaxxer,
‎我向你保证 ‎接下来的你一点也不喜欢
I can guarantee you, you will not like this next bit.
‎但如果你整场节目都能欢乐带过
But if you've been laughing the whole way through the show
‎结果突然这时候停下来
and you suddenly stop now,
‎大家就都了了
everyone will know.
‎所以你也不希望这样
So if that's not what you want to happen...
‎建议你这样做
just do a bit of this.
‎你肯定不喜欢 但这样做就对了
You will not be enjoying it. Just do a bit of that.
‎好了 反疫苗人士 就假装你是对的
All right, anti-vaxxers. Let's pretend you're right.
‎你实际上不是
You're not.
‎假装不是科学 但我们来…
Pretending is not science, but let's...
Let's im-- Let's pretend you're right, that vaccinations cause autism.
‎我们来假装你是对的 ‎疫苗引发自闭症
‎事实上并不会
They don't.
‎现在怎样
Now what?
‎因为就存在自闭症范围内的人
Because, as somebody who exists on the autism spectrum,
‎让我来对你说
let me say this to you.
‎我非常乐意身在其中
I'm happy to take one for the team.
‎我并不是说自闭症很容易
And I'm not suggesting that autism is easy.
‎绝对不是 非常艰难
It isn't. It is difficult.
‎我不会也无法否认
And I will not and cannot deny that.
‎但就算生命很苦 但能活着就很棒
But as difficult as this life is, it's nice to have a life,
and it's particularly nice to have that life
‎尤其是活在这样一个世界
一个没有
in a world without...
‎小儿麻痺症的世界
[yells] polio!
‎小儿麻痺症很不好
Polio is bad!
‎这是事实 不是感受
And that is a fact, not a feeling.
‎我宁愿罹患自闭症 ‎而不想跟你一样没良心
And I would much prefer to have autism than be a sociopath like you.
‎让我解释清楚
Let me explain.
‎如果你真的认为你的孩子 ‎你唯一的独生子
'Cause if you honestly think that your child, your only, single child,
‎比所有的孩子还重要…
is more important than all the other children collectively,
‎你根本就不想融入
you're not playing for the team.
‎如果你不想
And if you don't want to play for the team,
那你干嘛生孩子
why the fuck are you even having children?
‎找个石头宠物
Get a pet rock
把你的部落格删除
and delete your fucking blog!
‎终于抒发了
Got that off my chest.
‎我也很清楚 一旦这上线直播 ‎这小小的桥段…
Now, I do know that once this is streaming, that little bit...
‎将让我置身在反疫苗运动的
is opening me up to a whole world of a hate campaign
‎仇恨阵营世界里面
from the anti-vax movement.
‎但 千万别搞错 他们彼此协调
Because, make no mistake, they are coordinated.
‎不是随机 他们像个邪教
They are not random. They are a cult.
‎但我只是…
And I've only been...
‎我只是一次一个地方谈这话题
I've only been telling this material one room at a time,
‎而这仇恨就已经渗入
and the hate is already trickling in,
‎而且瞄准目标还有毒
and it is targeted, and it is venomous.
‎但我并不在意 ‎别担心
But it doesn't bother me. Don't worry about it.
我当点心
Like, I snack on it. "Mmm, nom, nom, nom."
‎真的…没事的
-It's really... It's fine. -
‎你知道我为什么这么做 ‎我为何把仇恨当点心 你懂了吗
You have worked out why I do that, yeah? Why I snack on hate? You've worked it out?
‎这是你增强免疫的方法 ‎叫做微量用药
It's how you build up immunity. It's called micro-dosing.
‎是的 你的仇恨就是我的疫苗
Yeah. Your hate is my vaccine.
‎你还能怎么样 ‎我已经罹患自闭症了
What are you gonna do? I've already got autism.
‎我罹患所谓的高效自闭症
I have what's called high-functioning autism,
‎这名字相当可怕
which is a terrible name for what I have,
‎因为这让大家以为我效能高
because it gives the impression that I function highly.
‎我才没有
- -I do not.
‎让你们了解处于光谱范畴内 ‎是什么感觉
To give you an idea of what it feels like to be on the spectrum,
basically, it feels like being the only sober person in a room full of drunks.
‎基本上说来就是在一间 ‎众人皆醉我独醒的房间里
‎或是相反的情况
Or the other way around.
‎基本上就是你跟每一个人格格不入
Basically, everyone is operating on a wavelength you can't quite key into.
‎让你用看的
To give you a visual...
‎这个女人…
This woman...
‎就是在自闭症光谱范畴下 ‎那就是…
is on the spectrum. That is...
‎我他妈的生活故事
the story of my fucking life.
‎真的 “上周同样时间 ‎同样地点的丧礼
Honestly. "Oh, it was a funeral same place, same time last week.
‎我为何没收到通知
Why didn't I get the memo?
‎他们干嘛亲嘴 我不喜欢那声音
Why are they kissing? I don't like the sound."
‎我从没收过通知 从来没有
I never get the memo. I never do.
我永远错过通知
I've always missed the memo.
‎我记得很清楚 ‎从身为老师的爱将
I remember going from being the teacher's pet
‎到课堂中把老师的克星带来
to bring the teacher's nemesis in one lesson.
‎直到被诊断出来之前 ‎我从不明白究竟发生了什么事
And until I was diagnosed, I never understood what had happened.
The lesson was on prepositions, so strap yourselves in for this story.
‎那堂课上的是介词 ‎所以各位听之前先系好安全带了
‎我的确喜欢我的老师 ‎她是位好老师
Now, I do like my teacher. She was a good teacher.
I liked the way she explained things, but we lost each other this way.
‎我喜欢她解释的方式 ‎但因此我们误解彼此
‎她一开始上课是这样的 ‎“想象一个盒子”
This is how she began the lesson. She said, "Imagine a box."
‎这我行 我生来就爱想象
And I could do that. I was gifted to a point.
‎脑海里就出现扎扎实实的盒子
Visual thinker. Good box, solid.
‎立体朴实但存在的盒子
Three-dimensional, nothing fancy, but there.
‎接着她说“介词…
And then she said, "A preposition
is a word that explains your relationship to the box."
‎是解释你跟盒子关系的字”
‎我的思绪在此瓦解
And that's when my thinking just fell apart,
‎因为我心想“我跟盒子有关 ”
because I thought, "I'm related to a box?"
‎接着她又说了 ‎“现在你可以在盒子后面
Then she said, "Now, you can be behind the box.
‎有人知道那里是什么介词 ”
Does anybody know what the preposition is there?"
‎他们不知道 但我有问题
No, they didn't, but I had a question.
‎我说“我是盒子生的吗 ”
I said, "Am I made of box?"
‎让我解释一下我的想法
Now, let me bring you into my thinking there.
‎我认为如果我跟盒子有关 ‎我们一定有相同的基因
I thought if I was related to a box, we must share DNA,
‎所以我脑袋里的逻辑
and it made more sense in my head
that I would be made of box than the box would be made of me.
‎我是盒子生的 ‎而不是盒子是我生的
‎但我老师从来不知道
But my teacher was not privy
‎我脑袋瓜里打转的这一切想法
to that gifted train of thought circling my head there.
‎她有点惊讶 然后说 ‎“不 汉娜 妳不是盒子生的
So she was a bit thrown, and she said, "No, Hannah, you're not made of box.
‎我很惊讶妳会这么问
I'm surprised you had to ask that.
‎好 那妳可以到盒子前面
So, okay, you can be in front of the box then.
‎有没有人知道那里的介词是什么 ”
Does anybody know what the preposition is there?"
‎不 他们不知道 但我又有问题了
No, they didn't. But I had another question.
‎我说“这盒子有名字吗 ”
I said, "Does the box have a name?"
‎我认为如果我有了名字 ‎我就能搞清楚我们什么关系
I thought if I had a name, I could work out how we were related.
‎也许我们是亲戚
Maybe we were cousins.
‎她说“不 只是盒子
And she said, "No, it's a box.
‎盒子没有名字 汉娜
- -Boxes don't have names, Hannah.
‎你知道哪个盒子有名字的吗 ”
What boxes do you know have names?"
‎我开始列出早餐谷片
And I started listing breakfast cereals.
‎她说“好的 够了
She's like, "All right, okay.
‎你可以在盒子旁边 ‎有人知道那里是什么介词 ”
You can be beside the box. Does anybody know what the preposition is there?"
‎不 他们不知道
No, they didn't.
但我又有问题了
-But I had another question. -
‎我不记得我这问题后面的逻辑
I don't remember my thinking behind this question,
‎但我记得我问了 ‎因为我问的时候 大家都笑了
but I remember asking it, because when I did, everybody laughed
‎我根本搞不清楚原因
and I had no idea why.
‎但我记得真的非常喜欢那种感受
But I remembered really liking the feeling.
‎问题是这样的
This was the question.
‎我说“我可以吃盒子吗 ”
I said, "Am I allowed to eat the box?"
‎当然 大家都在笑 ‎就剩老师跟我没笑
Of course, yes, everybody is laughing, except me and the teacher.
‎回头想想 我不知道她为何没笑
Looking back, I don't know why the fuck she wasn't laughing.
‎就笑话的角度 这算经典了
-As far as jokes go, that's a classic. -
‎一个小蕾丝边在问盒子（阴道俚语）能不能吃
A baby dyke just asked if she was allowed to eat the box.
‎她不觉得好笑 ‎她回答“好了 够了”
She didn't think it was funny. She was like, "Okay. All right. Okay.
Calm down. Okay, we might be on the wrong track.
‎冷静 好了 我们可能有点误会
‎不然我们想想另外跟盒子有关的
How about we imagine something else in relation to the box then?
‎好吗 企鹅如何
Okay? How about a penguin?
‎现在 企鹅可以在盒子里面
Now, the penguin can be inside the box.
‎有人知道那里该用什么介词 ”
Does anybody know what the preposition is there?"
‎不 他们不知道 ‎但我对于企鹅有个天杀的问题
No, they didn't, but I had some fucking questions about the penguin.
‎我问“企鹅是什么生的 ”
- -I said, "What is the penguin made of?"
‎这就是让我老师 ‎崩溃的最后一根稻草了
And that was the question that broke my teacher.
‎你知道老师什么时候抓狂
You know you've broken a teacher
‎就是从不出口成脏的老师‎满嘴脏话的当下
when a teacher who never swears swears bad.
‎我继续问“企鹅是什么生的 ”
So I went, "What's the penguin made of?"
‎她就说“企鹅 我是说…
And she's like, "Penguin? I mean... [exhales]
‎是他娘的企鹅生的”
It's made of fucking penguin!"
‎就答案来说 这太甜美了…
And as far as answers go, that's... mwah."
‎简直是无懈可击
- -Like, that is watertight.
‎这是个精彩的回答
That is a stunning answer.
‎绝对没有其他逻辑
You can't logic out of that answer.
绝对是个好答案
That is a good answer.
‎但到那时候 我才觉得 ‎“我也许误会大了”
At that point, I thought, "I might be on the wrong track."
‎但我还有其他的问题
But I had other questions pressing,
‎但我心想“现在不是时候 ‎她好像抓狂了”
but I thought, "Now doesn't seem the time. She seems upset."
‎所以我想“我还是把问题缓一缓好了”
So what I thought is, "I might hang on to my question."
‎我当时这样想 但我错了
That's what I thought, and that was my mistake.
‎趁我们僵持的时候 ‎我该直接问才对
I should have asked my question then while we were in the thick of it...
‎否则都没有了
or not at all.
‎因为我做了最差的处理
Because I did the worst possible thing.
‎我等到她感觉安全以后
I waited until she felt safe.
‎接着我问了我的问题
Then I asked my question.
‎但我等了很久 ‎甚至到了别堂课
But I waited so long, it wasn't even the same lesson.
‎是那天后来的阅读课
It was much later in the day, in silent reading.
‎我等了这么久 甚至都不算是问题了
I waited so long, it wasn't even a question anymore.
‎比较像是理论 结果搞得更糟
It was more of a theory, and that made it worse.
‎我问“要是如果…
I said, "What if...
‎企鹅吃了盒子怎么办
the penguin ate the box?
‎那么你不觉得 ‎企鹅也算是盒子生的 ”
Wouldn't then you say the penguin's a little bit made of box?"
‎她说“出去”
She's like, "Get out."
‎那是第一次 但并非最后一次 ‎我觉得我莫名其妙地
And that was the first, but not the last time, I was sent out
‎被赶出教室
for reasons I had no idea why.
‎因为问题是我非常投入在那堂课里
Because the thing is, I was genuinely engaged in that lesson.
‎我真的想知道是什么介词
Like, I really-- I really wanted to know what a preposition was.
‎我不是坐在那里说“介词
I wasn't sitting there going, "Prepositions?
‎我他娘的从没听过”
[yells] I've never fucking heard of them!"
‎但她后来跟我解释
But as she explained to me later,
‎她说“你在故意装傻（顿角）”
she said, "You were being deliberately obtuse."
‎我回答“但我不是三角形”
I'm like, "But I'm not a triangle."
‎那天我没学到介词
I did not learn what a preposition was that day.
‎我现在学会了 那都过去了
Look, I understand what they are now. I'm all over it.
‎我也明白如果企鹅吃盒子
And I also understand, if the penguin ate the box...
‎那企鹅就在盒子的周围
the penguin would be around the box.
‎老实说 我被诊断出自闭症的那天 ‎简直就是晴空万里
Honestly, the day I was formally diagnosed with autism was a very good day.
‎因为那像是有人给了我一把 ‎我的自我城市的大门钥匙
Because it felt like I'd been handed the keys to the city of me.
‎因为我终于搞懂
Because I was able to make sense
‎许多一直困惑我的事情
of so many things that had only ever been confusing to me.
‎像是为何我这么聪明 ‎还要拼命留下证据
Like why I could be so intelligent but struggle to leave any proof.
‎为何我不会填表格 为何…
Why I can't fill in forms. Why...
‎为何我这一辈子都感到 ‎如此深沈的孤立
Wh-- Why I felt such a profound sense of isolation my entire life,
‎不论我多努力想融入大家
despite trying so hard to be part of the team.
‎这是光谱范畴下的大事 ‎就是寂寞
And that is a big thing about being on the spectrum. It is lonely.
I find it very difficult to connect to others,
‎我感觉与他人建立关系非常困难
‎因为我的脑袋把我带到 ‎无人居住的地方
because my brain takes me to places where nobody else lives.
‎你不能一开始跟人
And you can't just start talking to people
‎在狗公园里谈道格拉斯凹陷
about the Pouch of Douglas at the dog park.
People do not like it. And I tried more than once.
‎大家不喜欢 我试过不只一次
‎但我不是在此要求你们怜悯 ‎我在此是干扰你们的自信
But I'm not here to collect your pity. I'm here to disrupt your confidence.
‎因为我显然努力用了方法 ‎分享我的想法
Because, clearly, I've worked out a way to share my thinking.
‎不是吗
Haven't I?
‎这叫什么随便你
Like, you can call this whatever the fuck you need to call this.
‎独白
A monologue.
说教
A lecture.
‎你说“西红柿” ‎我说“蕃茄酱 繁忙街道”
You say "Tomato," I say, "Ketchup, busy road."
‎让我让你好懂一些
Let me dumb it down for you.
‎本节目是解释
What this show is
你认为你觉得
is a metaphorical preposition that explains the relationship
‎你了解我所想的与我真正能想的
between what you think you think you see me think...
‎这两者间的暗喻介词
and what I'm genuinely able to think.
‎因为我喜欢我想的方式
Because I like the way that I think.
‎如果这世界是对的 而我身处其中
If the world is right and I'm right in it,
‎我可以找到我的扩增拉链 ‎我的思考就能扩充
I can find my funny zip and my thinking expands.
‎我思考的方式有其瑰丽之处
There is beauty in the way that I think.
I don't think outside the box.
‎我并非跳脱传统思考
But, as it turns out, if I ask nicely,
‎但 结果却是 ‎如果我有礼貌地问
‎是的 我可以吃盒子
yes, I am allowed to eat the box.
‎你瞧
Oh, look.
[applause]
Sponsored by McDonald's.
‎由麦当劳赞助
‎你看得见他吗
Can you see him? Can you see him?
‎好个讨厌鬼
What a cunt.
Now, this is Saint Bernard.
‎这是圣伯纳
‎那是圣伯纳 那是圣母
That's Saint Bernard, that's the Virgin Mary,
‎那是耶稣宝宝 那是头小狮子
that's the baby JC, and that is a tiny lion.
‎你看得出来这幅画主要在干嘛
Now, can you see the main action that's going on in this picture?
‎‎你看得出来他们在干嘛 圣母…
Can you see what's happening? The Virgin Mary...
‎乳汁喷在他天杀的脸上
is lactating on his fucking face.
‎祝你今天顺心
-[squirting sound] -G'day.
‎这家伙说
Now, this guy's going,
“你知道 ‎我通常是画里最怪的
"You know, look, I'm-- I'm usually the weirdest thing in a picture.
I'm a tiny lion."
‎我是头小狮子“
‎但牠不是
But he's not though,
because the Virgin Mary is lactating on his fucking face.
‎因为圣母朝他脸上喷乳汁
‎这张画说明伯纳如何成为圣伯纳
Now, this picture tells the story of how Bernard became Saint Bernard.
‎以前 他只是普通的老伯纳
One day, he was regular old Bernard.
‎然后他看见了个景象
And then he had a vision.
‎在那个景象中 圣母出现在他眼前…
And in that vision, the Virgin Mary appeared to him...
‎然后朝他脸上喷乳汁
and lactated on his fucking face.
‎我并不批评这家伙 ‎我们都有梦来着
Now, I'm not judging the bloke. We've all had the dreams.
‎我们都梦过 接着起床后 ‎对自己说
We've all had them, where we wake up and go,
“我还不知道自己有这一面”
"I did not know that about myself."
‎没事的
It's fine.
‎奇怪的事情是 他醒来后
What's weird though is he did not wake up and go,
"I might file that under 'Secret.'"
‎说“我不打算当作秘密”
‎不 他没有这么做
No, that's not what he did.
‎他醒来之后说“我该告诉大家”
He woke up and said, "I'd better tell the fellas."
‎然后大家开会说“这太神了
And then the fellas have a meeting and go, "This is amazing.
‎我们最把这人视作圣人”
We'd better call this one a saint."
‎他现在成为圣人 因为… ‎什么
He's a saint now, 'cause... What? Sorry?
‎什么
What?
‎他成了圣人就因为他做了春梦
He's a saint 'cause what? He had a wet dream?
‎他居然就成了圣人
And now he's a fucking saint?
‎他目睹了喷乳汁的奇迹 ‎结果就成了圣人
He witnessed the miracle of lactation and now he's a saint?
‎他杜撰了自己的事 ‎现在却成了天杀的…
He made it about himself, and now he's a fuck...
‎这水平也太低了
This is a low bar.
‎这就是男人命名一切事物的证据
This is proof men have named all the things
‎而且支配整个游戏
and rigged the fucking game.
‎这还不够
This is not enough.
‎那就来谈谈菁英体制
Let's talk about a meritocracy.
‎这位是圣则济利亚
Now, this is Saint Cecilia.
‎她得学天杀的大提琴
She had to learn the fucking cello!
‎小伯做了什么
What did Bernie do?
It is not enough.
‎这还不够
Isn't it weird that the cello has been invented,
‎发明大提琴而没发明乐谱架
‎不是很奇怪吗
but not the music stand?
Why are they still relying on small, naked babies?
‎为何他们还要靠裸体小孩
‎这是我最爱的一幅画
This is my favorite painting.
‎这是《阿尔巴女爵》 由西班牙伟大的艺术家哥雅所绘
This is The Duchess of Alba by the great Spanish artist Goya.
‎我喜欢是因为 ‎她付了一大笔钱画这幅画
I love it because she would have paid a pretty penny for this portrait,
and she paid that pretty penny
‎她也的确付了那笔钱
just so she could tell people for centuries to come...
‎让她可以后世的所有人
‎她有穿鞋
that she's got shoes on.
"I've got shoes on! I've got shoes on!
‎“我有穿鞋 各位 ‎我有穿鞋”
各位 ‎我有穿鞋
Y'all, I got shoes on!"
‎这是我想想在狗公园里 ‎那只小灵狗说的话
That is what I imagine the whippet was saying in the dog park.
‎“我有穿鞋”
"I got shoes on!"
‎女人卡在岩石里
Women getting stuck to rocks
‎是女人有史以来的第二嗜好
is the number two hobby of ladies of all time.
All time.
‎一直以来都是
This is under... This one's made of rock.
‎这是在…这是石头刻的
They are just getting stuck. Look, what is happening here?
‎她们就是卡在那里 ‎究竟发生什么事情
‎看…这是…什么情况
-Like just... Like, what? -
That is a salty, salty body of water.
‎那是海水
‎她根本没在游泳
Like, she's not swimming.
她只是靠屁屁滑过表面
She's just skating across the surface on her fanny.
‎你的膝盖在干嘛
What do you do with your knees?
‎猫中风了
Cat's had a stroke.
‎这家伙说“感谢老天 你没穿衣服 ‎我在画风景画”
This guy went, "Thank God you're in the nude. I'm painting a landscape."
‎这是个巨婴
That's a big baby.
‎那是个肥仔
That is a chunker.
‎她得拉开道格拉斯凹陷的开伞绳 ‎才能放进去
She would have had to pull the ripcord on the Pouch of Douglas to fit that.
‎《维伦多尔夫的维纳斯》
This is the Venus of Willendorf.
‎她早于古希腊的美感 ‎你知道这是什么时候刻的
She predates ancient Greek beauty ideals. Do you know when this was carved?
‎旧时器时代
Paleolithic times.
‎我在进行原始人节食法 混帐
I'm on the paleo, motherfuckers.
I am on the paleo.
‎原始人饮食法
‎这家伙在史莱哲林
This man is in Slytherin.
‎这家伙在赫夫帕夫
This man is in Hufflepuff.
‎这是有名的医师
Look, he's a famoso doctor.
"I'm Dr. Cock Biscotti. I wear two hats."
‎“我是混帐意大利饼干医师 ‎我戴两顶帽子”
‎各位 这是凯伦 ‎就是她
This is Karen, everybody. Here she is.
小凯
There's Kaz.
‎她篮子两手满满把篮子装满 ‎厉害 小凯
There she is, picking her basketful of handfuls. Good on you, Kaz.
‎还在葡萄藤上
Still on the vine.
‎这样保鲜比较久
Keeps them fresher for longer.
‎为什么是这决定
Why this decision?
‎居然这样决定
That is a decision!
‎那宝宝可以在盒子上
That baby could be on the box.
‎他可以在盒子旁边 ‎他可以当天杀的企鹅
He could be beside the box. He could be a fucking penguin!
‎为什么 做这决定
Why? That is a decision!
‎这也是著名的路易CK首张画像
It's also the first known portrait of Louis C.K.
♪ Douglas Douglass, apple tree ♪
♪ Have a wife, now let her be ♪
♪ Give me, give me what you got ♪
♪ I'm gonna make you what you're not ♪
[cheering and applause continues]
♪ Douglas Douglass, prickly pear ♪
♪ Have a wife, but I don't care ♪
♪ Give me, give me all your soul ♪
♪ I'm gonna dip you in my bowl ♪
♪ Long way down ♪
♪ It's a long way down ♪
♪ And he knows ♪
♪ Douglas Douglass, sticky pine ♪
♪ Have a wife, and that's just fine ♪
♪ Give me, give me what I need ♪
♪ You know I gots to plant your seed ♪